#!/bin/bash
#SBATCH --job-name=data-proc
#SBATCH --partition=gpu-rtx6k
#SBATCH --account=cse
#SBATCH --nodes=1
#SBATCH --cpus-per-task=8
#SBATCH --mem=32G
#SBATCH --gres=gpu:1
#SBATCH --time=1-00:00:00 
#SBATCH --mail-type=ALL
#SBATCH --mail-user=tjung2@uw.edu

# I use source to initialize conda into the right environment.
cat $0
echo "--------------------"

source ~/.bashrc
conda activate ckl

# python run.py --config configs/templama/training/t5_kadapters_yearly_2freeze.json -checkpoint_path outputs/wmtbaseline_full/epoch=0-f1_score=0.151-em_score=0.000.ckpt

python preprocess_wmt_train_data.py 2007 -debug
--------------------
Stricker Ends Drought With Barclays Win
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.5744517, 'index': 1, 'word': 'St', 'start': 0, 'end': 2}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.5746072, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Barclay', 'start': 27, 'end': 34}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.4716509, 'index': 10, 'word': '##s', 'start': 34, 'end': 35}
Filed at 6:25 p.m.
HARRISON, N.Y. (AP) -- What looked like more heartache for Steve Stricker turned into the sweetest victory of his career.
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9582494, 'index': 1, 'word': 'H', 'start': 0, 'end': 1}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.7754622, 'index': 2, 'word': '##AR', 'start': 1, 'end': 3}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.764008, 'index': 3, 'word': '##RI', 'start': 3, 'end': 5}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.84995264, 'index': 4, 'word': '##SO', 'start': 5, 'end': 7}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.8366478, 'index': 5, 'word': '##N', 'start': 7, 'end': 8}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.94156724, 'index': 7, 'word': 'N', 'start': 10, 'end': 11}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.9984934, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Y', 'start': 12, 'end': 13}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9954599, 'index': 12, 'word': 'AP', 'start': 16, 'end': 18}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9996985, 'index': 23, 'word': 'Steve', 'start': 59, 'end': 64}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99961275, 'index': 24, 'word': 'St', 'start': 65, 'end': 67}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9851007, 'index': 25, 'word': '##rick', 'start': 67, 'end': 71}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.94781065, 'index': 26, 'word': '##er', 'start': 71, 'end': 73}
After going 6 1/2 years and 146 tournaments without winning, Stricker birdied four of his last five holes Sunday at The Barclays for a stunning turnaround that gave him a 2-under 69 and a two-shot victory over K.J. Choi.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9987911, 'index': 14, 'word': 'St', 'start': 61, 'end': 63}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.8896279, 'index': 15, 'word': '##rick', 'start': 63, 'end': 67}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.4994457, 'index': 16, 'word': '##er', 'start': 67, 'end': 69}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.97718006, 'index': 27, 'word': 'The', 'start': 116, 'end': 119}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.9956809, 'index': 28, 'word': 'Barclay', 'start': 120, 'end': 127}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.9952342, 'index': 29, 'word': '##s', 'start': 127, 'end': 128}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99962217, 'index': 50, 'word': 'K', 'start': 210, 'end': 211}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.86927354, 'index': 51, 'word': '.', 'start': 211, 'end': 212}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9810768, 'index': 52, 'word': 'J', 'start': 212, 'end': 213}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.7310492, 'index': 53, 'word': '.', 'start': 213, 'end': 214}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99915445, 'index': 54, 'word': 'Choi', 'start': 215, 'end': 219}
"It was hard, but it was fun," Stricker said, his voice choking as tears streamed down the side of his face.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99843735, 'index': 12, 'word': 'St', 'start': 31, 'end': 33}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.94919795, 'index': 13, 'word': '##rick', 'start': 33, 'end': 37}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.51197, 'index': 14, 'word': '##er', 'start': 37, 'end': 39}
I never knew if I was going to win again.
It sure wasn't easy.
Not with 10 players -- five of them major champions -- separated by three shots.
And not with Choi holing two birdie putts that were a combined 95 feet, making it look as if he were destined to win.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9989519, 'index': 4, 'word': 'Choi', 'start': 13, 'end': 17}
Stricker, who already let four chances of winning slip away this year, refused to buckle.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9991695, 'index': 1, 'word': 'St', 'start': 0, 'end': 2}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.86140645, 'index': 2, 'word': '##rick', 'start': 2, 'end': 6}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.43381053, 'index': 3, 'word': '##er', 'start': 6, 'end': 8}
And when his final birdie from 8 feet dropped into the cup, he raised his arms and hugged his caddie, Tom Matthews, who first caddied for Stricker when he won the 2001 Match Play Championship in Australia.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99969286, 'index': 26, 'word': 'Tom', 'start': 102, 'end': 105}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.999678, 'index': 27, 'word': 'Matthews', 'start': 106, 'end': 114}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9980211, 'index': 35, 'word': 'St', 'start': 138, 'end': 140}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9115333, 'index': 36, 'word': '##rick', 'start': 140, 'end': 144}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.6241365, 'index': 42, 'word': '2001', 'start': 163, 'end': 167}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.6165469, 'index': 43, 'word': 'Match', 'start': 168, 'end': 173}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99729246, 'index': 44, 'word': 'Play', 'start': 174, 'end': 178}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9985033, 'index': 45, 'word': 'Championship', 'start': 179, 'end': 191}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99975985, 'index': 47, 'word': 'Australia', 'start': 195, 'end': 204}
Even without Tiger Woods, the inaugural PGA Tour Playoffs got off to a rousing start.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.96981734, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Tiger', 'start': 13, 'end': 18}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9915338, 'index': 4, 'word': 'Woods', 'start': 19, 'end': 24}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.99886835, 'index': 8, 'word': 'PGA', 'start': 40, 'end': 43}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99883384, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Tour', 'start': 44, 'end': 48}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9925032, 'index': 10, 'word': 'Play', 'start': 49, 'end': 53}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9938198, 'index': 11, 'word': '##offs', 'start': 53, 'end': 57}
Along with the fourth victory of his career, Stricker moved to the top of the FedEx Cup standings with 2,050-point lead over Choi, who closed with a 70.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9984939, 'index': 10, 'word': 'St', 'start': 45, 'end': 47}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.6847579, 'index': 11, 'word': '##rick', 'start': 47, 'end': 51}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.580028, 'index': 12, 'word': '##er', 'start': 51, 'end': 53}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9980637, 'index': 19, 'word': 'Fed', 'start': 78, 'end': 81}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99656034, 'index': 20, 'word': '##E', 'start': 81, 'end': 82}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.997597, 'index': 21, 'word': '##x', 'start': 82, 'end': 83}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9987181, 'index': 22, 'word': 'Cup', 'start': 84, 'end': 87}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99876773, 'index': 33, 'word': 'Choi', 'start': 125, 'end': 129}
Rory Sabbatini, who had a share of the lead at the turn, closed with a 68 to finish another stroke back and moved up to No.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9997077, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Rory', 'start': 0, 'end': 4}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99980783, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Sa', 'start': 5, 'end': 7}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99946874, 'index': 3, 'word': '##bba', 'start': 7, 'end': 10}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99260265, 'index': 4, 'word': '##tin', 'start': 10, 'end': 13}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99702656, 'index': 5, 'word': '##i', 'start': 13, 'end': 14}
3 in the playoff race.
Woods skipped the first of four playoff events and tumbled to No.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.999031, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Woods', 'start': 0, 'end': 5}
4, nearly 5,000 points behind Stricker.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9990955, 'index': 9, 'word': 'St', 'start': 30, 'end': 32}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.87285197, 'index': 10, 'word': '##rick', 'start': 32, 'end': 36}
The next stop is the Deutsche Bank Championship outside Boston, which starts Friday.
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9981824, 'index': 6, 'word': 'Deutsche', 'start': 21, 'end': 29}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99718827, 'index': 7, 'word': 'Bank', 'start': 30, 'end': 34}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99851376, 'index': 8, 'word': 'Championship', 'start': 35, 'end': 47}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99461687, 'index': 10, 'word': 'Boston', 'start': 56, 'end': 62}
There are three tournaments remaining before someone captures the $10 million deferred bonus, but all Stricker cared about was hoisting another trophy.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99874353, 'index': 20, 'word': 'St', 'start': 102, 'end': 104}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.5652703, 'index': 21, 'word': '##rick', 'start': 104, 'end': 108}
His last victory on U.S. soil came 11 years ago at the Western Open, when he was considered one of the bright young American players.
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9995245, 'index': 5, 'word': 'U', 'start': 20, 'end': 21}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.9970483, 'index': 6, 'word': '.', 'start': 21, 'end': 22}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.9987811, 'index': 7, 'word': 'S', 'start': 22, 'end': 23}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.9957325, 'index': 8, 'word': '.', 'start': 23, 'end': 24}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9992841, 'index': 16, 'word': 'Western', 'start': 55, 'end': 62}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9986932, 'index': 17, 'word': 'Open', 'start': 63, 'end': 67}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9997009, 'index': 28, 'word': 'American', 'start': 116, 'end': 124}
But his game slowly began to slide until he lost his PGA Tour card two years ago, and spent the winter in Wisconsin hitting balls from the inside of a remodeled trailer to a frozen driving range.
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.99874693, 'index': 12, 'word': 'PGA', 'start': 53, 'end': 56}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9986683, 'index': 13, 'word': 'Tour', 'start': 57, 'end': 61}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99973476, 'index': 24, 'word': 'Wisconsin', 'start': 106, 'end': 115}
After four close calls -- two of them in majors -- Stricker finally became a PGA Tour winner again.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99937403, 'index': 14, 'word': 'St', 'start': 51, 'end': 53}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9399237, 'index': 15, 'word': '##rick', 'start': 53, 'end': 57}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9988033, 'index': 20, 'word': 'PGA', 'start': 77, 'end': 80}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9987152, 'index': 21, 'word': 'Tour', 'start': 81, 'end': 85}
Choi was going after his third victory of the year, and everything was falling his way.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99914813, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Choi', 'start': 0, 'end': 4}
He took a share of the lead with a 45-foot birdie putt on No.
12, dropping his putter in surprise, then took the lead again with a 50-foot birdie putt on the 15th.
Stricker hung his head, but not for long.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9988377, 'index': 1, 'word': 'St', 'start': 0, 'end': 2}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.94963896, 'index': 2, 'word': '##rick', 'start': 2, 'end': 6}
He answered with a 12-foot birdie on the par-3 16th to regain a share of the lead, then hit wedge that stopped 4 feet from the cup for birdie on the 17th that gave him a one-shot margin.
Choi hit his approach left of the par-5 18th green and could chip no closer than 15 feet, from which he made par.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99902976, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Choi', 'start': 0, 'end': 4}
Stricker finished at 16-under 268 and earned $1.26 million.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9987319, 'index': 1, 'word': 'St', 'start': 0, 'end': 2}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.621408, 'index': 2, 'word': '##rick', 'start': 2, 'end': 6}
Geoff Ogilvy, playing down the road from his U.S. Open title last year at Winged Foot, closed with a 69 and tied for fourth with Mark Calcavecchia (65) and two-time Westchester champion Ernie Els (68).
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99980223, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Geoff', 'start': 0, 'end': 5}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99978477, 'index': 2, 'word': 'O', 'start': 6, 'end': 7}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9989281, 'index': 3, 'word': '##gi', 'start': 7, 'end': 9}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9973099, 'index': 4, 'word': '##l', 'start': 9, 'end': 10}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.999305, 'index': 5, 'word': '##vy', 'start': 10, 'end': 12}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9951778, 'index': 13, 'word': 'U', 'start': 45, 'end': 46}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.74808687, 'index': 14, 'word': '.', 'start': 46, 'end': 47}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.98939914, 'index': 15, 'word': 'S', 'start': 47, 'end': 48}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.98020226, 'index': 16, 'word': '.', 'start': 48, 'end': 49}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99831694, 'index': 17, 'word': 'Open', 'start': 50, 'end': 54}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9922528, 'index': 22, 'word': 'Wing', 'start': 74, 'end': 78}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.99215764, 'index': 23, 'word': '##ed', 'start': 78, 'end': 80}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.9894948, 'index': 24, 'word': 'Foot', 'start': 81, 'end': 85}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99979305, 'index': 35, 'word': 'Mark', 'start': 129, 'end': 133}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99971366, 'index': 36, 'word': 'Cal', 'start': 134, 'end': 137}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99910206, 'index': 37, 'word': '##ca', 'start': 137, 'end': 139}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.98396045, 'index': 38, 'word': '##ve', 'start': 139, 'end': 141}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9725474, 'index': 39, 'word': '##cchi', 'start': 141, 'end': 145}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.71227944, 'index': 48, 'word': 'West', 'start': 165, 'end': 169}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.80030197, 'index': 49, 'word': '##chester', 'start': 169, 'end': 176}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9997877, 'index': 51, 'word': 'Ernie', 'start': 186, 'end': 191}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9997843, 'index': 52, 'word': 'El', 'start': 192, 'end': 194}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9996921, 'index': 53, 'word': '##s', 'start': 194, 'end': 195}
Another shot back was Rich Beem, who had a share of the lead early in the final round and had to settle for a small consolation.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.999738, 'index': 5, 'word': 'Rich', 'start': 22, 'end': 26}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9997763, 'index': 6, 'word': 'Bee', 'start': 27, 'end': 30}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9995296, 'index': 7, 'word': '##m', 'start': 30, 'end': 31}
He was at No.
134 in the playoff standings, and his tie for seventh moved him up to No.
113, getting him into the next round.
"I'm in next week," Beem said.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9801088, 'index': 10, 'word': 'Bee', 'start': 20, 'end': 23}
"I've got to play just as well next week to get to Chicago" for the third event.
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9994428, 'index': 16, 'word': 'Chicago', 'start': 51, 'end': 58}
Doug LaBelle also picked up a minor victory.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9997641, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Doug', 'start': 0, 'end': 4}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9997658, 'index': 2, 'word': 'La', 'start': 5, 'end': 7}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99968153, 'index': 3, 'word': '##B', 'start': 7, 'end': 8}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9992808, 'index': 4, 'word': '##elle', 'start': 8, 'end': 12}
He closed with a 68, making a 6-foot birdie on his final hole, and wound up at No.
120 in the standings to qualify for the Deutsche Bank Championship.
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.99779314, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Deutsche', 'start': 40, 'end': 48}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99646264, 'index': 10, 'word': 'Bank', 'start': 49, 'end': 53}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99823564, 'index': 11, 'word': 'Championship', 'start': 54, 'end': 66}
Had he missed the putt, his FedEx Cup season would have been over.
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9974608, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Fed', 'start': 28, 'end': 31}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9971417, 'index': 10, 'word': '##E', 'start': 31, 'end': 32}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9980794, 'index': 11, 'word': '##x', 'start': 32, 'end': 33}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99869287, 'index': 12, 'word': 'Cup', 'start': 34, 'end': 37}
Ryan Armour and Bill Haas were among those who had a chance to move into the top 120 and avoid elimination, but Haas had four bogeys in a five-hole stretch on the back, and Armour had back-to-back bogeys late in his round.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99977016, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Ryan', 'start': 0, 'end': 4}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99981934, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Arm', 'start': 5, 'end': 8}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99973416, 'index': 3, 'word': '##our', 'start': 8, 'end': 11}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.999793, 'index': 5, 'word': 'Bill', 'start': 16, 'end': 20}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99981815, 'index': 6, 'word': 'Haas', 'start': 21, 'end': 25}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.999133, 'index': 25, 'word': 'Haas', 'start': 112, 'end': 116}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9980019, 'index': 43, 'word': 'Arm', 'start': 173, 'end': 176}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.91327894, 'index': 44, 'word': '##our', 'start': 176, 'end': 179}
Brett Quigley was sweating it, too, especially when he saw a scoreboard behind the 17th green that incorrectly projected him to finish at No.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9997872, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Brett', 'start': 0, 'end': 5}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9997856, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Q', 'start': 6, 'end': 7}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9993262, 'index': 3, 'word': '##ui', 'start': 7, 'end': 9}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9996774, 'index': 4, 'word': '##gley', 'start': 9, 'end': 13}
He rolled in a 20-foot birdie putt, then birdied the 18th for a 67 to make it with room to spare.
"More drama than I needed," Quigley said.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99868363, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Q', 'start': 28, 'end': 29}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.97822195, 'index': 10, 'word': '##ui', 'start': 29, 'end': 31}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.5237505, 'index': 11, 'word': '##gley', 'start': 31, 'end': 35}
I never felt that nervous trying to win a tournament.
The Barclays didn't lack for drama at the top of the leaderboard, either.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99771565, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Barclay', 'start': 4, 'end': 11}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.99156207, 'index': 3, 'word': '##s', 'start': 11, 'end': 12}
A tentative start by the leaders allowed for someone to get hot and join the fray, and there were plenty of volunteers.
Sabbatini ran off five birdies on the front nine.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99948066, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Sa', 'start': 0, 'end': 2}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.8912948, 'index': 2, 'word': '##bba', 'start': 2, 'end': 5}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.47996977, 'index': 3, 'word': '##tin', 'start': 5, 'end': 8}
Calcavecchia had six birdies in a seven-hole stretch around the turn.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.86524194, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Cal', 'start': 0, 'end': 3}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.6404729, 'index': 2, 'word': '##ca', 'start': 3, 'end': 5}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.91165954, 'index': 3, 'word': '##ve', 'start': 5, 'end': 7}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.2526278, 'index': 4, 'word': '##cchi', 'start': 7, 'end': 11}
Phil Mickelson opened with three straight birdies, only to lose his momentum with a double bogey at No.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99980766, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Phil', 'start': 0, 'end': 4}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9998113, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Mick', 'start': 5, 'end': 9}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9996582, 'index': 3, 'word': '##els', 'start': 9, 'end': 12}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9983542, 'index': 4, 'word': '##on', 'start': 12, 'end': 14}
4 when he found trouble in the trees and missed a 4-foot putt.
Mickelson shot 67 and tied for seventh, his first top 10 on the PGA Tour since winning The Players Championship in May.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9996976, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Mick', 'start': 0, 'end': 4}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.6258022, 'index': 2, 'word': '##els', 'start': 4, 'end': 7}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.5623058, 'index': 3, 'word': '##on', 'start': 7, 'end': 9}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9988415, 'index': 17, 'word': 'PGA', 'start': 64, 'end': 67}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99868464, 'index': 18, 'word': 'Tour', 'start': 68, 'end': 72}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9975613, 'index': 21, 'word': 'The', 'start': 87, 'end': 90}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99633056, 'index': 22, 'word': 'Players', 'start': 91, 'end': 98}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9983982, 'index': 23, 'word': 'Championship', 'start': 99, 'end': 111}
Meanwhile, no one in the final group made a birdie until Stricker with a 10-foot birdie at No.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9992744, 'index': 14, 'word': 'St', 'start': 57, 'end': 59}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.987799, 'index': 15, 'word': '##rick', 'start': 59, 'end': 63}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.8907669, 'index': 16, 'word': '##er', 'start': 63, 'end': 65}
Even so, he had a share of the lead with Sabbatini as he headed for the back nine that seemed loaded with possibilities.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9994364, 'index': 12, 'word': 'Sa', 'start': 41, 'end': 43}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.93276525, 'index': 13, 'word': '##bba', 'start': 43, 'end': 46}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.34969848, 'index': 14, 'word': '##tin', 'start': 46, 'end': 49}
Choi did not figure to be in the mix.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99898535, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Choi', 'start': 0, 'end': 4}
He was 3 over for his round through eight holes and appeared to be out of contention until a two-putt birdie on No.
9, and a bunker shot to tap-in range for birdie on the 10th.
Then came his theatrics with the putter, the two long birdies on the 12th and 15th and left him smiling and pumping his fist.
The final act, however, belonged to Stricker.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9990526, 'index': 9, 'word': 'St', 'start': 36, 'end': 38}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9342192, 'index': 10, 'word': '##rick', 'start': 38, 'end': 42}
He last played this tournament in 1996, tying for 60th, and thought so little of the place that he told his wife to "take a picture because we're not coming back."
The best picture of all was Stricker posing with a trophy.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9992583, 'index': 7, 'word': 'St', 'start': 28, 'end': 30}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9595675, 'index': 8, 'word': '##rick', 'start': 30, 'end': 34}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.8939542, 'index': 9, 'word': '##er', 'start': 34, 'end': 36}
Spies, Lies and FISA - New York Times
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.82283026, 'index': 7, 'word': '##IS', 'start': 17, 'end': 19}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.93336856, 'index': 8, 'word': '##A', 'start': 19, 'end': 20}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.97784686, 'index': 10, 'word': 'New', 'start': 23, 'end': 26}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9801831, 'index': 11, 'word': 'York', 'start': 27, 'end': 31}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9450488, 'index': 12, 'word': 'Times', 'start': 32, 'end': 37}
As Democratic lawmakers try to repair a deeply flawed bill on electronic eavesdropping, the White House is pumping out the same fog of fear and disinformation it used to push the bill through Congress this summer.
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9997714, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Democratic', 'start': 3, 'end': 13}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99889237, 'index': 21, 'word': 'White', 'start': 92, 'end': 97}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.99774456, 'index': 22, 'word': 'House', 'start': 98, 'end': 103}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9986824, 'index': 42, 'word': 'Congress', 'start': 192, 'end': 200}
President Bush has been telling Americans that any change would deny the government critical information, make it easier for terrorists to infiltrate, expose state secrets, and make it harder “to save American lives.”
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99956185, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Bush', 'start': 10, 'end': 14}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9996001, 'index': 6, 'word': 'Americans', 'start': 32, 'end': 41}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9997142, 'index': 38, 'word': 'American', 'start': 201, 'end': 209}
There is no truth to any of those claims.
No matter how often Mr. Bush says otherwise, there is also no disagreement from the Democrats about the need to provide adequate tools to fight terrorists.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9990926, 'index': 7, 'word': 'Bush', 'start': 24, 'end': 28}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9997364, 'index': 18, 'word': 'Democrats', 'start': 84, 'end': 93}
The debate is over whether this should be done constitutionally, or at the whim of the president.
The 1978 Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act, or FISA, requires a warrant to intercept international communications involving anyone in the United States.
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9961872, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Foreign', 'start': 9, 'end': 16}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9976982, 'index': 4, 'word': 'Intelligence', 'start': 17, 'end': 29}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9984268, 'index': 5, 'word': 'Sur', 'start': 30, 'end': 33}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9967243, 'index': 6, 'word': '##ve', 'start': 33, 'end': 35}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9973429, 'index': 7, 'word': '##illa', 'start': 35, 'end': 39}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99753624, 'index': 8, 'word': '##nce', 'start': 39, 'end': 42}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9984442, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Act', 'start': 43, 'end': 46}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9870687, 'index': 12, 'word': 'F', 'start': 51, 'end': 52}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.61702764, 'index': 13, 'word': '##IS', 'start': 52, 'end': 54}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9891392, 'index': 14, 'word': '##A', 'start': 54, 'end': 55}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99966383, 'index': 27, 'word': 'United', 'start': 142, 'end': 148}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.99935716, 'index': 28, 'word': 'States', 'start': 149, 'end': 155}
A secret court has granted these warrants quickly nearly every time it has been asked.
After 9/11, the Patriot Act made it even easier to conduct surveillance, especially in hot pursuit of terrorists.
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9973329, 'index': 7, 'word': 'Patriot', 'start': 16, 'end': 23}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99866885, 'index': 8, 'word': 'Act', 'start': 24, 'end': 27}
But that was not good enough for the Bush team, which was determined to use the nation’s tragedy to grab ever more power for its vision of an imperial presidency.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99857265, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Bush', 'start': 37, 'end': 41}
Mr. Bush ignored the FISA law and ordered the National Security Agency to intercept phone calls and e-mail between people abroad and people in the United States without a warrant, as long as “the target” was not in this country.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99918854, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Bush', 'start': 4, 'end': 8}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.7893637, 'index': 6, 'word': 'F', 'start': 21, 'end': 22}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.6365476, 'index': 7, 'word': '##IS', 'start': 22, 'end': 24}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9841779, 'index': 8, 'word': '##A', 'start': 24, 'end': 25}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9993715, 'index': 13, 'word': 'National', 'start': 46, 'end': 54}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.99936175, 'index': 14, 'word': 'Security', 'start': 55, 'end': 63}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9991393, 'index': 15, 'word': 'Agency', 'start': 64, 'end': 70}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99968606, 'index': 31, 'word': 'United', 'start': 147, 'end': 153}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.99940395, 'index': 32, 'word': 'States', 'start': 154, 'end': 160}
The president did not announce his decision.
He allowed a few lawmakers to be briefed but withheld key documents.
The special intelligence court was in the dark until The Times disclosed the spying in December 2005.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99846214, 'index': 10, 'word': 'The', 'start': 53, 'end': 56}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9980118, 'index': 11, 'word': 'Times', 'start': 57, 'end': 62}
Mr. Bush still refused to stop.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99922, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Bush', 'start': 4, 'end': 8}
He claimed that FISA was too limiting for the Internet-speed war against terror.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9986011, 'index': 4, 'word': 'F', 'start': 16, 'end': 17}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.88171893, 'index': 5, 'word': '##IS', 'start': 17, 'end': 19}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.99267036, 'index': 6, 'word': '##A', 'start': 19, 'end': 20}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.99676204, 'index': 12, 'word': 'Internet', 'start': 46, 'end': 54}
But he never explained those limits and rebuffed lawmakers’ offers to legally accommodate his concerns.
This year, the administration found an actual problem with FISA: It requires a warrant to eavesdrop on communications between foreigners that go through computers in the United States.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99786764, 'index': 11, 'word': 'F', 'start': 59, 'end': 60}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.65968275, 'index': 12, 'word': '##IS', 'start': 60, 'end': 62}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.96279514, 'index': 13, 'word': '##A', 'start': 62, 'end': 63}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99963963, 'index': 34, 'word': 'United', 'start': 170, 'end': 176}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.9994136, 'index': 35, 'word': 'States', 'start': 177, 'end': 183}
It was a problem that did not exist in 1978, and it had an easy fix.
But Mr. Bush’s lawyers tacked dangerous additions onto a bill being rushed through Congress before the recess.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9969434, 'index': 4, 'word': 'Bush', 'start': 8, 'end': 12}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99861854, 'index': 17, 'word': 'Congress', 'start': 83, 'end': 91}
When the smoke cleared, Congress had fixed the real loophole, but also endorsed the idea of spying without court approval.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9992782, 'index': 6, 'word': 'Congress', 'start': 24, 'end': 32}
It gave legal cover to more than five years of illegal spying.
Fortunately, the law is to expire in February, and some Democratic legislators are trying to fix it.
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9996963, 'index': 14, 'word': 'Democratic', 'start': 56, 'end': 66}
House members have drafted a bill, which is a big improvement but still needs work.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9935198, 'index': 1, 'word': 'House', 'start': 0, 'end': 5}
The Senate is working on its bill, and we hope it will show the courage this time to restore the rule of law to American surveillance programs.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9987075, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Senate', 'start': 4, 'end': 10}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.999767, 'index': 26, 'word': 'American', 'start': 112, 'end': 120}
There are some red lines, starting with the absolute need for court supervision of any surveillance that can involve American citizens or others in the United States.
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9997736, 'index': 21, 'word': 'American', 'start': 117, 'end': 125}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9996132, 'index': 27, 'word': 'United', 'start': 152, 'end': 158}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.9993839, 'index': 28, 'word': 'States', 'start': 159, 'end': 165}
The bill passed in August allowed the administration to inform the FISA court about its methods and then issue blanket demands for data to communications companies without any further court approval or review.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9990475, 'index': 12, 'word': 'F', 'start': 67, 'end': 68}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.8371242, 'index': 13, 'word': '##IS', 'start': 68, 'end': 70}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.99527866, 'index': 14, 'word': '##A', 'start': 70, 'end': 71}
The House bill would permit the government to conduct surveillance for 45 days before submitting it to court review and approval.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9975551, 'index': 2, 'word': 'House', 'start': 4, 'end': 9}
Mr. Bush is wrong when he says the bill would slow down intelligence gathering.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9988637, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Bush', 'start': 4, 'end': 8}
After that, ideally, the law would require a real warrant.
If Congress will not do that, at a minimum it must require spying programs to undergo periodic audits by the court and Congress.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9988959, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Congress', 'start': 3, 'end': 11}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99888134, 'index': 25, 'word': 'Congress', 'start': 119, 'end': 127}
The administration wants no reviews.
Mr. Bush and his team say they have safeguards to protect civil liberties, meaning surveillance will be reviewed by the attorney general, the director of national intelligence and the inspectors general of the Justice Department and the Central Intelligence Agency.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99914896, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Bush', 'start': 4, 'end': 8}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9988794, 'index': 40, 'word': 'Justice', 'start': 210, 'end': 217}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9988812, 'index': 41, 'word': 'Department', 'start': 218, 'end': 228}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99945897, 'index': 44, 'word': 'Central', 'start': 237, 'end': 244}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.999185, 'index': 45, 'word': 'Intelligence', 'start': 245, 'end': 257}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.999188, 'index': 46, 'word': 'Agency', 'start': 258, 'end': 264}
There are two enormous flaws in that.
The Constitution is based on the rule of law, not individuals; giving such power to any president would be un-American.
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.79135525, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Constitution', 'start': 4, 'end': 16}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9991887, 'index': 24, 'word': 'American', 'start': 110, 'end': 118}
And this one long ago showed he cannot be trusted.
Last week, The Times reported that the C.I.A. director, Gen. Michael V. Hayden, is investigating the office of his agency’s inspector general after it inquired into policies on detention and interrogation.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9990412, 'index': 4, 'word': 'The', 'start': 11, 'end': 14}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9986922, 'index': 5, 'word': 'Times', 'start': 15, 'end': 20}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9981151, 'index': 9, 'word': 'C', 'start': 39, 'end': 40}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.6349471, 'index': 10, 'word': '.', 'start': 40, 'end': 41}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.99851596, 'index': 11, 'word': 'I', 'start': 41, 'end': 42}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9880399, 'index': 12, 'word': '.', 'start': 42, 'end': 43}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.996527, 'index': 13, 'word': 'A', 'start': 43, 'end': 44}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.8492373, 'index': 14, 'word': '.', 'start': 44, 'end': 45}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99949485, 'index': 19, 'word': 'Michael', 'start': 61, 'end': 68}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9980342, 'index': 20, 'word': 'V', 'start': 69, 'end': 70}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.96601576, 'index': 21, 'word': '.', 'start': 70, 'end': 71}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99940395, 'index': 22, 'word': 'Hayden', 'start': 72, 'end': 78}
This improper, perhaps illegal investigation sends a clear message of intimidation.
We also know that the F.B.I. has abused expanded powers it was granted after 9/11 and that the former attorney general, Alberto Gonzales, systematically covered up the president’s actions with deliberately misleading testimony.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9973453, 'index': 6, 'word': 'F', 'start': 22, 'end': 23}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.69166243, 'index': 7, 'word': '.', 'start': 23, 'end': 24}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.99756235, 'index': 8, 'word': 'B', 'start': 24, 'end': 25}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.98946667, 'index': 9, 'word': '.', 'start': 25, 'end': 26}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9972632, 'index': 10, 'word': 'I', 'start': 26, 'end': 27}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.90770304, 'index': 11, 'word': '.', 'start': 27, 'end': 28}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9996077, 'index': 30, 'word': 'Alberto', 'start': 120, 'end': 127}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9994951, 'index': 31, 'word': 'Go', 'start': 128, 'end': 130}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9989649, 'index': 32, 'word': '##nza', 'start': 130, 'end': 133}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.97756726, 'index': 33, 'word': '##les', 'start': 133, 'end': 136}
Mr. Bush says the law should give immunity to communications companies that gave data to the government over the last five years without a court order.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9994813, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Bush', 'start': 4, 'end': 8}
He says they should not be punished for helping to protect America, but what Mr. Bush really wants is to avoid lawsuits that could uncover the extent of the illegal spying he authorized after 9/11.
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9997565, 'index': 12, 'word': 'America', 'start': 59, 'end': 66}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9977544, 'index': 18, 'word': 'Bush', 'start': 81, 'end': 85}
It may be possible to shield these companies from liability, since the government lied to them about the legality of its requests.
But the law should allow suits aimed at forcing disclosure of Mr. Bush’s actions.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99873465, 'index': 14, 'word': 'Bush', 'start': 66, 'end': 70}
It should also require a full accounting to Congress of all surveillance conducted since 9/11.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99900347, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Congress', 'start': 44, 'end': 52}
And it should have an expiration date, which the White House does not want.
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99881387, 'index': 12, 'word': 'White', 'start': 49, 'end': 54}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.9982494, 'index': 13, 'word': 'House', 'start': 55, 'end': 60}
Ever since 9/11, we have watched Republican lawmakers help Mr. Bush shred the Constitution in the name of fighting terrorism.
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.99977136, 'index': 10, 'word': 'Republican', 'start': 33, 'end': 43}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9976789, 'index': 16, 'word': 'Bush', 'start': 63, 'end': 67}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9455347, 'index': 21, 'word': 'Constitution', 'start': 78, 'end': 90}
We have seen Democrats acquiesce or retreat in fear.
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.99969596, 'index': 4, 'word': 'Democrats', 'start': 13, 'end': 22}
It is time for that to stop.
Torre Says Offer Showed Lack of Trust
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.89377856, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 0, 'end': 5}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.83403563, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Say', 'start': 6, 'end': 9}
His duties now include cleaning the garage, shopping for groceries and cooking dinner.
With no job lined up for next summer, Joe Torre said he may see the major horse races or show up at Wimbledon.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9997852, 'index': 10, 'word': 'Joe', 'start': 38, 'end': 41}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9997149, 'index': 11, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 42, 'end': 47}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9765778, 'index': 24, 'word': 'Wimbledon', 'start': 100, 'end': 109}
His charitable work will continue.
But Torre's itinerary, in his new life as the former manager of the Yankees, does not include a trip to Yankee Stadium.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9979896, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 4, 'end': 9}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99899715, 'index': 19, 'word': 'Yankees', 'start': 68, 'end': 75}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99565053, 'index': 27, 'word': 'Yankee', 'start': 104, 'end': 110}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.9979126, 'index': 28, 'word': 'Stadium', 'start': 111, 'end': 118}
His personal assistant will pack up his photos and books and cigars.
"I walked out of there, and I'm not going back," Torre said yesterday.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99913377, 'index': 17, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 49, 'end': 54}
I just leave the memories.
Torre rejected the Yankees" contract offer on Thursday, but in a news conference at the Hilton Rye Town yesterday, he said he felt rejected by them.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99890625, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 0, 'end': 5}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9989461, 'index': 4, 'word': 'Yankees', 'start': 19, 'end': 26}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9906772, 'index': 18, 'word': 'Hilton', 'start': 88, 'end': 94}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.99688643, 'index': 19, 'word': 'R', 'start': 95, 'end': 96}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.9925356, 'index': 20, 'word': '##ye', 'start': 96, 'end': 98}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.9965194, 'index': 21, 'word': 'Town', 'start': 99, 'end': 103}
The wound is fresh, and Torre could not even say if he would throw out a ceremonial first pitch sometime after the Yankees open their new ballpark in 2009.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9993329, 'index': 7, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 24, 'end': 29}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99906194, 'index': 24, 'word': 'Yankees', 'start': 115, 'end': 122}
"If somebody wants you to do a job, and it takes them two weeks to figure out, yeah, "I guess we should do this," you're a little suspicious," Torre said, adding later, "If somebody wanted me to manage here, I'd be managing here."
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99775445, 'index': 40, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 143, 'end': 148}
Torre acknowledged that the $5 million the Yankees offered him was generous.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99869674, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 0, 'end': 5}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9990306, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Yankees', 'start': 43, 'end': 50}
But he said he felt insulted by the framework of the deal, which was heavily tied to incentives and not open to negotiation.
In a meeting Thursday in Tampa, Fla., the Yankees offered one year and Torre intimated that he wanted two.
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9979936, 'index': 6, 'word': 'Tampa', 'start': 25, 'end': 30}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99368805, 'index': 8, 'word': 'F', 'start': 32, 'end': 33}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.9741303, 'index': 9, 'word': '##la', 'start': 33, 'end': 35}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99929464, 'index': 13, 'word': 'Yankees', 'start': 42, 'end': 49}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99928164, 'index': 18, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 71, 'end': 76}
A team that spends lavishly for players was unwilling to give a second year to Torre, who reached the postseason in each of his 12 seasons but had not won a World Series in either of his last two contracts.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9991102, 'index': 17, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 79, 'end': 84}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9984256, 'index': 34, 'word': 'World', 'start': 157, 'end': 162}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99877, 'index': 35, 'word': 'Series', 'start': 163, 'end': 169}
The structure of the Yankees" proposal rewarded Torre with a $1 million bonus for each postseason round the team would achieve in 2008.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99837834, 'index': 5, 'word': 'Yankees', 'start': 21, 'end': 28}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9985982, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 48, 'end': 53}
But if he did not reach the World Series, he would not have exceeded this season's $7.5 million salary.
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9987875, 'index': 8, 'word': 'World', 'start': 28, 'end': 33}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99877894, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Series', 'start': 34, 'end': 40}
"The fact that somebody is reducing your salary is telling me they're not satisfied with what you're doing," Torre said.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.998954, 'index': 26, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 109, 'end': 114}
I think it was just the way it was offered, more so than the numbers involved.
Two years would have opened the door to have more discussions, and it never happened.
Torre said he would leave it to reporters to interpret whether the Yankees made him an offer they knew he would turn down.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99877834, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 0, 'end': 5}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9985274, 'index': 13, 'word': 'Yankees', 'start': 67, 'end': 74}
In a meeting that included the team's principal owner, George Steinbrenner; his sons, Hank and Hal; his son-in-law, Felix Lopez; Randy Levine, the team president; General Manager Brian Cashman; and Lonn Trost, the chief operating officer, Torre said he sensed that only one or two people wanted him back.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99960434, 'index': 13, 'word': 'George', 'start': 55, 'end': 61}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9995154, 'index': 14, 'word': 'Stein', 'start': 62, 'end': 67}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99758464, 'index': 15, 'word': '##bre', 'start': 67, 'end': 70}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.56372654, 'index': 16, 'word': '##nner', 'start': 70, 'end': 74}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9994709, 'index': 21, 'word': 'Hank', 'start': 86, 'end': 90}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99925953, 'index': 23, 'word': 'Hal', 'start': 95, 'end': 98}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9997623, 'index': 32, 'word': 'Felix', 'start': 116, 'end': 121}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99955773, 'index': 33, 'word': 'Lopez', 'start': 122, 'end': 127}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99980456, 'index': 35, 'word': 'Randy', 'start': 129, 'end': 134}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9996574, 'index': 36, 'word': 'Levine', 'start': 135, 'end': 141}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99977756, 'index': 44, 'word': 'Brian', 'start': 179, 'end': 184}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9996835, 'index': 45, 'word': 'Cash', 'start': 185, 'end': 189}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.98718655, 'index': 46, 'word': '##man', 'start': 189, 'end': 192}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99940443, 'index': 49, 'word': 'Lo', 'start': 198, 'end': 200}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.98252046, 'index': 50, 'word': '##nn', 'start': 200, 'end': 202}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9997543, 'index': 51, 'word': 'T', 'start': 203, 'end': 204}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9806842, 'index': 52, 'word': '##ros', 'start': 204, 'end': 207}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9992476, 'index': 53, 'word': '##t', 'start': 207, 'end': 208}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99865824, 'index': 60, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 239, 'end': 244}
One supporter, Torre said, was Cashman, who talked Steinbrenner out of firing him after the Yankees" 2006 playoff loss.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9986989, 'index': 4, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 15, 'end': 20}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.998946, 'index': 8, 'word': 'Cash', 'start': 31, 'end': 35}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9335368, 'index': 9, 'word': '##man', 'start': 35, 'end': 38}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99905294, 'index': 13, 'word': 'Stein', 'start': 51, 'end': 56}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99259764, 'index': 14, 'word': '##bre', 'start': 56, 'end': 59}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.8862111, 'index': 15, 'word': '##nner', 'start': 59, 'end': 63}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99873984, 'index': 22, 'word': 'Yankees', 'start': 92, 'end': 99}
Cashman was less vocal in his support this time, but he said he was not the only person who hoped Torre would accept.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.98927885, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Cash', 'start': 0, 'end': 4}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9988997, 'index': 23, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 98, 'end': 103}
"Everybody in that room wanted him back; I have to disagree with him there," Cashman said last night.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.997826, 'index': 19, 'word': 'Cash', 'start': 77, 'end': 81}
Joe knows I'm an ally because there's a bond there.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9988492, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Joe', 'start': 0, 'end': 3}
But I've got to speak for everybody else in the room, and they did want him back, too.
As Steinbrenner cedes control to his sons, he is more intent on seeking consensus for major moves.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99939686, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Stein', 'start': 3, 'end': 8}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9602831, 'index': 3, 'word': '##bre', 'start': 8, 'end': 11}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.88514835, 'index': 4, 'word': '##nner', 'start': 11, 'end': 15}
Levine said all of the executives wanted Torre back.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9993805, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Levine', 'start': 0, 'end': 6}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.7729442, 'index': 8, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 41, 'end': 46}
"Every single one of us made that offer with the hope that he would return," Levine said.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9984529, 'index': 19, 'word': 'Levine', 'start': 77, 'end': 83}
We were all disappointed that he did not accept it.
Reasonable people can differ.
Asked why the Yankees would not negotiate, Cashman said there were pressure points for both sides that made the deal unworkable.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9975146, 'index': 5, 'word': 'Yankees', 'start': 14, 'end': 21}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9989724, 'index': 10, 'word': 'Cash', 'start': 43, 'end': 47}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.83633935, 'index': 11, 'word': '##man', 'start': 47, 'end': 50}
"It's just complicated, given the dollars," Cashman said.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9881678, 'index': 13, 'word': 'Cash', 'start': 44, 'end': 48}
This was not the first time the Yankees had talked about a new contract for Torre.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99897957, 'index': 8, 'word': 'Yankees', 'start': 32, 'end': 39}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9969478, 'index': 16, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 76, 'end': 81}
Early in spring training, Torre indicated he would be willing to accept a one-year contract extension.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99883956, 'index': 6, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 26, 'end': 31}
Steve Swindal, who was then Steinbrenner's son-in-law, said a pay cut would be mandatory, but in any case, the Yankees wanted to wait until the season was over.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9998083, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Steve', 'start': 0, 'end': 5}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9997854, 'index': 2, 'word': 'S', 'start': 6, 'end': 7}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99923307, 'index': 3, 'word': '##wind', 'start': 7, 'end': 11}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9994443, 'index': 4, 'word': '##al', 'start': 11, 'end': 13}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99584323, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Stein', 'start': 28, 'end': 33}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.96861786, 'index': 10, 'word': '##bre', 'start': 33, 'end': 36}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.6166769, 'index': 11, 'word': '##nner', 'start': 36, 'end': 40}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.999114, 'index': 34, 'word': 'Yankees', 'start': 111, 'end': 118}
After a third consecutive first-round knockout, they would not give Torre the kind of deal he got last time, after winning six pennants in eight seasons.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9987319, 'index': 14, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 68, 'end': 73}
The new offer would have kept Torre as the majors" highest-paid manager, and while Torre bristled at the idea of incentives, ownership saw them as a way for him to exceed his 2007 salary.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9990329, 'index': 7, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 30, 'end': 35}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9989728, 'index': 19, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 83, 'end': 88}
Cashman said the incentive package would probably not be part of a new manager's contract.
Torre said Cashman told him about the offer on Wednesday night and warned that the Yankees were unlikely to adjust it.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9984293, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 0, 'end': 5}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9979549, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Cash', 'start': 11, 'end': 15}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.7119537, 'index': 4, 'word': '##man', 'start': 15, 'end': 18}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99797475, 'index': 17, 'word': 'Yankees', 'start': 83, 'end': 90}
But Torre said he wanted to fly to Tampa anyway.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9993168, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 4, 'end': 9}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9985155, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Tampa', 'start': 35, 'end': 40}
Cashman flew home on Wednesday and flew back with Torre on Thursday.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9674699, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Cash', 'start': 0, 'end': 4}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9522922, 'index': 11, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 50, 'end': 55}
On the flight, Torre said, Cashman asked him, "Are you going down to make a deal or to say goodbye?"
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9990642, 'index': 5, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 15, 'end': 20}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99645793, 'index': 8, 'word': 'Cash', 'start': 27, 'end': 31}
Torre said he did not know.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99896336, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 0, 'end': 5}
The meeting was brief - 20 minutes, Torre said - and although Steinbrenner was there, it was his younger son, Hal, who presented the offer and the rationale.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9987744, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 36, 'end': 41}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9993699, 'index': 14, 'word': 'Stein', 'start': 62, 'end': 67}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99045295, 'index': 15, 'word': '##bre', 'start': 67, 'end': 70}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.73424894, 'index': 16, 'word': '##nner', 'start': 70, 'end': 74}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9995052, 'index': 26, 'word': 'Hal', 'start': 110, 'end': 113}
Torre had incentives built into the contract he signed after the 2001 World Series, but he disputed the idea that he needed financial motivation to win in the postseason, which he called a crapshoot.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9981469, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 0, 'end': 5}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.99187356, 'index': 13, 'word': 'World', 'start': 70, 'end': 75}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9988441, 'index': 14, 'word': 'Series', 'start': 76, 'end': 82}
"I've been there for 12 years and I didn't think motivation was needed," Torre said.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9992268, 'index': 21, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 73, 'end': 78}
I just didn't think it was the right thing for me, and I didn't think it was the right thing for my players.
Any pressure that was caused by thinking the manager's going to lose his job, I didn't think we needed.
In a conference call with reporters on Thursday, Levine said the Yankees believed it was "important to motivate people, as most people in everyday life have to be, based on performance."
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9992863, 'index': 10, 'word': 'Levine', 'start': 49, 'end': 55}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9973674, 'index': 13, 'word': 'Yankees', 'start': 65, 'end': 72}
Levine is responsible for negotiating the Yankees" major contracts, and Torre had little to say about their relationship.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99922675, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Levine', 'start': 0, 'end': 6}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9979879, 'index': 7, 'word': 'Yankees', 'start': 42, 'end': 49}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9960347, 'index': 13, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 72, 'end': 77}
Torre said that, besides Cashman, he had little backing among the Yankees" hierarchy.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9988529, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 0, 'end': 5}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9982794, 'index': 6, 'word': 'Cash', 'start': 25, 'end': 29}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99789923, 'index': 15, 'word': 'Yankees', 'start': 66, 'end': 73}
"If something goes wrong, I understand a lot of questions are going to be asked," Torre said.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99926895, 'index': 20, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 82, 'end': 87}
"But I'd like to believe the support should come from the organization that, "He knows what he's doing."
It's not the money that is going to be the determining factor.
It's just going to be the commitment and trust - because you can't have one without the other - to manage the ball club.
Then Torre thanked Steinbrenner for trusting him to manage his team for 12 years.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99805015, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 5, 'end': 10}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9990031, 'index': 4, 'word': 'Stein', 'start': 19, 'end': 24}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.98418707, 'index': 5, 'word': '##bre', 'start': 24, 'end': 27}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9184729, 'index': 6, 'word': '##nner', 'start': 27, 'end': 31}
It is Steinbrenner's team, after all, and in winning more games for it than any manager besides Joe McCarthy, Torre is now an important part of its past.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9917267, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Stein', 'start': 6, 'end': 11}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.87654144, 'index': 4, 'word': '##bre', 'start': 11, 'end': 14}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.387083, 'index': 5, 'word': '##nner', 'start': 14, 'end': 18}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9997608, 'index': 24, 'word': 'Joe', 'start': 96, 'end': 99}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99958766, 'index': 25, 'word': 'McCarthy', 'start': 100, 'end': 108}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9170545, 'index': 27, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 110, 'end': 115}
Torre had played for each of the three teams he managed before Steinbrenner hired him, but he never played for the Yankees.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9989849, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 0, 'end': 5}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9970181, 'index': 13, 'word': 'Stein', 'start': 63, 'end': 68}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9684201, 'index': 14, 'word': '##bre', 'start': 68, 'end': 71}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.6767459, 'index': 15, 'word': '##nner', 'start': 71, 'end': 75}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9987156, 'index': 25, 'word': 'Yankees', 'start': 115, 'end': 122}
"I still feel very much like a visitor to this whole organization," he said.
Now Torre is a visitor again, officially, a proud and wounded one with no plans to stop by anytime soon.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9978379, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Torre', 'start': 4, 'end': 9}
The Gospel According to Mr. Colbert
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.43730322, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Gospel', 'start': 4, 'end': 10}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.5578487, 'index': 7, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 28, 'end': 35}
Have you heard the one about the actor working as a comedian who plays a talk show host who is pretending to run for president?
Tim Russert, the host of “Meet the Press” has, and he thinks it’s pretty funny, enough for 15 minutes on Sunday morning.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99979335, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Tim', 'start': 0, 'end': 3}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9996923, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Russ', 'start': 4, 'end': 8}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9996158, 'index': 3, 'word': '##ert', 'start': 8, 'end': 11}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99190015, 'index': 8, 'word': 'Meet', 'start': 26, 'end': 30}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9916716, 'index': 9, 'word': 'the', 'start': 31, 'end': 34}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.97052586, 'index': 10, 'word': 'Press', 'start': 35, 'end': 40}
Last week, Stephen Colbert, in his eponymous avatar as a nincompoop right-wing talk show host, went on “The Daily Show With Jon Stewart.” Amid a hail of blow kisses, he said he was mulling a run for leader of the free world and 15 minutes later on “The Colbert Report,” he declared, “I am doing it!” A trip to the altar of the Sunday morning talk show seemed like the next beat in the joke, which arrived on schedule yesterday when Mr. Colbert appeared on “Meet the Press.”
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99970764, 'index': 4, 'word': 'Stephen', 'start': 11, 'end': 18}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9994828, 'index': 5, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 19, 'end': 26}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.99455863, 'index': 28, 'word': 'The', 'start': 104, 'end': 107}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.98834974, 'index': 29, 'word': 'Daily', 'start': 108, 'end': 113}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99670786, 'index': 30, 'word': 'Show', 'start': 114, 'end': 118}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99938905, 'index': 32, 'word': 'Jon', 'start': 124, 'end': 127}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9922993, 'index': 33, 'word': 'Stewart', 'start': 128, 'end': 135}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.7975301, 'index': 63, 'word': 'The', 'start': 249, 'end': 252}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.7044608, 'index': 64, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 253, 'end': 260}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.74246174, 'index': 65, 'word': 'Report', 'start': 261, 'end': 267}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.65214807, 'index': 103, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 436, 'end': 443}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.5778395, 'index': 106, 'word': 'Meet', 'start': 457, 'end': 461}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.90578085, 'index': 107, 'word': 'the', 'start': 462, 'end': 465}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9133827, 'index': 108, 'word': 'Press', 'start': 466, 'end': 471}
“I’m doing it, Tim, because I think that our country is facing unprecedented challenges in the future,” Mr. Colbert said. “I think the junctures that we face are both critical and unforeseen, and the real challenge is how we will respond to these junctures, be they critical, or God help us, unforeseen.”
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9993273, 'index': 6, 'word': 'Tim', 'start': 15, 'end': 18}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9971917, 'index': 24, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 108, 'end': 115}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9929525, 'index': 67, 'word': 'God', 'start': 279, 'end': 282}
Mr. Russert showed he could play ball — he gamely challenged Mr. Colbert to name the official amphibian of Mr. Colbert’s home state, South Carolina.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.8280437, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Russ', 'start': 4, 'end': 8}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.6966285, 'index': 4, 'word': '##ert', 'start': 8, 'end': 11}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.91974854, 'index': 16, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 65, 'end': 72}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9469738, 'index': 27, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 111, 'end': 118}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9995109, 'index': 32, 'word': 'South', 'start': 133, 'end': 138}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.9994418, 'index': 33, 'word': 'Carolina', 'start': 139, 'end': 147}
The result was eerie, although not particularly funny, because it didn’t seem any more like parody than the discussions on the other three Sunday morning shows.
Sunday morning talk shows are a kind of civic liturgy, a comfy place where the singers may change from week to week, but the hymnal never does.
In this sacrament, petitioners strive to appear both learned and humane, while the hosts serve as self-appointed prelates for the public.
Mr. Russert’s Sunday morning eminence is unchallenged, in part because of his ability to convey regular-guy gravitas and eyebrow-borne skepticism while demonstrating a mastery of political matters.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.8198678, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Russ', 'start': 4, 'end': 8}
In a hot, crowded presidential season, candidates show up on Sunday to trade the risk of embarrassment for the chance to break through the clutter.
Sort of like an appearance on “The Colbert Report,” come to think of it, only without the possibility of belly laughs.
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9947552, 'index': 8, 'word': 'The', 'start': 31, 'end': 34}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.98673403, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 35, 'end': 42}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99184895, 'index': 10, 'word': 'Report', 'start': 43, 'end': 49}
There might be those who will suggest that the presence of Mr. Colbert on the hallowed ground of “Meet the Press” is a sign that paradigms are in the midst of shifting, but it is just a simple commercial exchange of brands: The funny guy who makes a living acting serious talking with the serious guy who was temporarily making a living acting funny.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9908462, 'index': 14, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 63, 'end': 70}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.96522385, 'index': 21, 'word': 'Meet', 'start': 98, 'end': 102}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9539884, 'index': 22, 'word': 'the', 'start': 103, 'end': 106}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9609067, 'index': 23, 'word': 'Press', 'start': 107, 'end': 112}
Mr. Russert said at the top of the show that “Meet the Press” has a long history of political humor, but Mr. Colbert and the standard issue Washington comic — say, Mark Russell — are not the same species.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.57104665, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Russ', 'start': 4, 'end': 8}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.62840366, 'index': 4, 'word': '##ert', 'start': 8, 'end': 11}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9822367, 'index': 13, 'word': 'Meet', 'start': 46, 'end': 50}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9185161, 'index': 14, 'word': 'the', 'start': 51, 'end': 54}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9346854, 'index': 15, 'word': 'Press', 'start': 55, 'end': 60}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9965657, 'index': 27, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 109, 'end': 116}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99940753, 'index': 32, 'word': 'Washington', 'start': 140, 'end': 150}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9996839, 'index': 36, 'word': 'Mark', 'start': 164, 'end': 168}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9987243, 'index': 37, 'word': 'Russell', 'start': 169, 'end': 176}
As Mr. Colbert demonstrated on Sunday morning, it isn’t that he finds the Beltway’s folkways amusing, he finds them appalling.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.8150004, 'index': 4, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 7, 'end': 14}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9704595, 'index': 17, 'word': 'Belt', 'start': 74, 'end': 78}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.98670477, 'index': 18, 'word': '##ways', 'start': 78, 'end': 83}
It is Mr. Colbert’s ability to both mimic and amplify the tics of political convention and play them back with just a little more topspin that makes his satire so discomfiting.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.70089686, 'index': 5, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 10, 'end': 17}
His last notable engagement with the Beltway — his appearance at the White House Correspondents’ Association dinner in 2006 — drew withering reviews from the elites in attendance and an overwhelming, ecstatic response from YouTube nation.
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9706323, 'index': 7, 'word': 'Belt', 'start': 37, 'end': 41}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.9922456, 'index': 8, 'word': '##way', 'start': 41, 'end': 44}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.87629205, 'index': 13, 'word': 'White', 'start': 69, 'end': 74}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9702132, 'index': 14, 'word': 'House', 'start': 75, 'end': 80}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.99348235, 'index': 15, 'word': 'Co', 'start': 81, 'end': 83}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.8946255, 'index': 16, 'word': '##rre', 'start': 83, 'end': 86}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.98380774, 'index': 17, 'word': '##sp', 'start': 86, 'end': 88}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.97322, 'index': 18, 'word': '##ond', 'start': 88, 'end': 91}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9931964, 'index': 19, 'word': '##ents', 'start': 91, 'end': 95}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9936159, 'index': 20, 'word': 'Association', 'start': 97, 'end': 108}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.5542231, 'index': 44, 'word': 'YouTube', 'start': 223, 'end': 230}
The reason that the journalists found Mr. Colbert so offensive was not because he disrespected the president; it was his decision to show them up, calling them “fools” and suggesting that they are part of a self-sustaining apparatus.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99455154, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 42, 'end': 49}
On “Meet the Press,” Mr. Colbert’s agenda was prosaic: He was trying to leverage his show and a faux candidacy in support of a new book.
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.5719731, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Meet', 'start': 4, 'end': 8}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.7816097, 'index': 3, 'word': 'the', 'start': 9, 'end': 12}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.571459, 'index': 4, 'word': 'Press', 'start': 13, 'end': 18}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9943757, 'index': 8, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 25, 'end': 32}
For Mr. Russert and other mainstream media types (Maureen Dowd of The New York Times got in on the fun even before he announced by turning over a column to Mr. Colbert), the transaction is more nuanced.
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.5158809, 'index': 4, 'word': 'Russ', 'start': 8, 'end': 12}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.80368584, 'index': 5, 'word': '##ert', 'start': 12, 'end': 15}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9997357, 'index': 12, 'word': 'Maureen', 'start': 50, 'end': 57}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9997075, 'index': 13, 'word': 'Dow', 'start': 58, 'end': 61}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99851024, 'index': 14, 'word': '##d', 'start': 61, 'end': 62}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9972322, 'index': 16, 'word': 'The', 'start': 66, 'end': 69}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.99911046, 'index': 17, 'word': 'New', 'start': 70, 'end': 73}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.99881554, 'index': 18, 'word': 'York', 'start': 74, 'end': 78}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.99875486, 'index': 19, 'word': 'Times', 'start': 79, 'end': 84}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9779302, 'index': 37, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 160, 'end': 167}
Mr. Russert demonstrated that he could not only take a joke, but also that he was in on it, and could create a spicy point of entry for a demographic that network news almost never touches — anyone under 50.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.6706234, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Russ', 'start': 4, 'end': 8}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.70040625, 'index': 4, 'word': '##ert', 'start': 8, 'end': 11}
But the message I draw from Mr. Colbert is not that members of the media-political complex need to laugh at themselves, but that they need to take a hard look.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.97825336, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 32, 'end': 39}
The incipient generation of news consumers has made it clear that it does not want to see a bunch of guys with really nice neckware standing on the White House lawn talking about what they did not learn in the press room behind them and then flick at “sources” who suggest that “one thing is clear.”
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99927944, 'index': 33, 'word': 'White', 'start': 148, 'end': 153}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.99890107, 'index': 34, 'word': 'House', 'start': 154, 'end': 159}
One thing is, in fact, clear, from the plummeting numbers for network news: the jig is up.
Consumers have decided that network news and talk shows are every bit as fake and not nearly as funny as “The Daily Show” and “The Colbert Report.”
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.97684604, 'index': 22, 'word': 'The', 'start': 106, 'end': 109}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.94433856, 'index': 23, 'word': 'Daily', 'start': 110, 'end': 115}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.98401713, 'index': 24, 'word': 'Show', 'start': 116, 'end': 120}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.978957, 'index': 26, 'word': 'The', 'start': 127, 'end': 130}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9487713, 'index': 27, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 131, 'end': 138}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.96705306, 'index': 28, 'word': 'Report', 'start': 139, 'end': 145}
“Why shouldn’t a comedic fake newscaster feel right at home in a news format that itself verges on fakery?” said Mark Feldstein, a journalism professor at George Washington University. “After all, these shows aren’t all that different from televised wrestling, with the shouts and grunts that simulate combat during what is really a fixed fight, followed by everyone involved in the charade going out for drinks afterward.”
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.999748, 'index': 26, 'word': 'Mark', 'start': 113, 'end': 117}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9997213, 'index': 27, 'word': 'Fe', 'start': 118, 'end': 120}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9753376, 'index': 28, 'word': '##ld', 'start': 120, 'end': 122}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9958436, 'index': 29, 'word': '##stein', 'start': 122, 'end': 127}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99545264, 'index': 35, 'word': 'George', 'start': 155, 'end': 161}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.99662465, 'index': 36, 'word': 'Washington', 'start': 162, 'end': 172}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9929902, 'index': 37, 'word': 'University', 'start': 173, 'end': 183}
On television, and on the campaign, everybody is playing someone else; Mr. Colbert is just a bit more upfront about it.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9823498, 'index': 17, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 75, 'end': 82}
“Everybody is asking, ‘Is this real?,’” he said during his appearance. “And to which I would say to everybody, ‘This is not a dream, you are not going to wake up from this.’ I am far realer than Sam Brownback, let me put it that way.”
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99949354, 'index': 47, 'word': 'Sam', 'start': 195, 'end': 198}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9985219, 'index': 48, 'word': 'Brown', 'start': 199, 'end': 204}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.92935413, 'index': 49, 'word': '##back', 'start': 204, 'end': 208}
For decades, my 84-year-old father in Minnesota has taken a church-and-state approach to Sunday mornings: First church, then Sunday morning talk, sometimes phoning me afterward with updates about who said what.
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9997984, 'index': 12, 'word': 'Minnesota', 'start': 38, 'end': 47}
Mr. Colbert’s appearance left him scratching his head.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.8957882, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 4, 'end': 11}
“I don’t even know what Comedy Central is,” he said. “What cable station is it on?
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.93011916, 'index': 7, 'word': 'Comedy', 'start': 24, 'end': 30}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.8255931, 'index': 8, 'word': 'Central', 'start': 31, 'end': 38}
My wife wondered what it was all about, and we decided that it was a nut that is supposed to be serious.
Who the hell really cares about that?” I could say the same thing when he calls me about the more routine fare, but that would be an attack on his civic-mindedness.
My dad excused himself because he had taped ABC’s “This Week,” where Senator Joe Biden, another candidate with no real shot at winning, was taking a turn.
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.994439, 'index': 10, 'word': 'ABC', 'start': 44, 'end': 47}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99811685, 'index': 11, 'word': '##s', 'start': 48, 'end': 49}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.998166, 'index': 12, 'word': 'This', 'start': 51, 'end': 55}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.99833924, 'index': 13, 'word': 'Week', 'start': 56, 'end': 60}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9997143, 'index': 17, 'word': 'Joe', 'start': 77, 'end': 80}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9996522, 'index': 18, 'word': 'B', 'start': 81, 'end': 82}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.69156927, 'index': 19, 'word': '##iden', 'start': 82, 'end': 86}
CBS’s “Face the Nation” had former Massachusetts Gov. Mitt Romney, while “Fox News Sunday” had Senator John McCain and former Arkansas Gov. Mike Huckabee.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.82426864, 'index': 1, 'word': 'CBS', 'start': 0, 'end': 3}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.86353284, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Face', 'start': 7, 'end': 11}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.935996, 'index': 4, 'word': 'the', 'start': 12, 'end': 15}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.66099304, 'index': 5, 'word': 'Nation', 'start': 16, 'end': 22}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9990378, 'index': 8, 'word': 'Massachusetts', 'start': 35, 'end': 48}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9993788, 'index': 12, 'word': 'Mi', 'start': 54, 'end': 56}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9976871, 'index': 13, 'word': '##tt', 'start': 56, 'end': 58}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9989375, 'index': 14, 'word': 'Romney', 'start': 59, 'end': 65}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.91050726, 'index': 17, 'word': 'Fox', 'start': 74, 'end': 77}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.6039439, 'index': 18, 'word': 'News', 'start': 78, 'end': 82}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.5410203, 'index': 19, 'word': 'Sunday', 'start': 83, 'end': 89}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9995437, 'index': 22, 'word': 'John', 'start': 103, 'end': 107}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99974334, 'index': 23, 'word': 'McCain', 'start': 108, 'end': 114}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9991147, 'index': 26, 'word': 'Arkansas', 'start': 126, 'end': 134}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9997585, 'index': 30, 'word': 'Mike', 'start': 140, 'end': 144}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.999667, 'index': 31, 'word': 'Hu', 'start': 145, 'end': 147}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.5261637, 'index': 32, 'word': '##ck', 'start': 147, 'end': 149}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.93754256, 'index': 33, 'word': '##abe', 'start': 149, 'end': 152}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.51995456, 'index': 34, 'word': '##e', 'start': 152, 'end': 153}
No ratings are available yet, but I’m betting this first straw poll since Mr. Colbert entered the race went to the distinguished gentleman from Comedy Central.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.8025003, 'index': 8, 'word': 'I', 'start': 34, 'end': 35}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99049085, 'index': 18, 'word': 'Colbert', 'start': 78, 'end': 85}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9479759, 'index': 28, 'word': 'Comedy', 'start': 144, 'end': 150}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9756474, 'index': 29, 'word': 'Central', 'start': 151, 'end': 158}
Montana and Kansas Take on Big Coal
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9997456, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Montana', 'start': 0, 'end': 7}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99964064, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Kansas', 'start': 12, 'end': 18}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.923512, 'index': 6, 'word': 'Big', 'start': 27, 'end': 30}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.94919956, 'index': 7, 'word': 'Coal', 'start': 31, 'end': 35}
On Saturday, The Times’s business section featured two reports from unexpected parts of the country that should cheer the bipartisan coalition in the Senate that wants to move ahead quickly on legislation limiting emissions of carbon dioxide, the main global warming gas.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.7255177, 'index': 4, 'word': 'The', 'start': 13, 'end': 16}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9779426, 'index': 5, 'word': 'Times', 'start': 17, 'end': 22}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9234877, 'index': 6, 'word': '##s', 'start': 23, 'end': 24}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9989331, 'index': 29, 'word': 'Senate', 'start': 150, 'end': 156}
The reports provide further evidence, if any were needed, that Congress should not listen to the coal industry’s siren call for special treatment.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9991228, 'index': 13, 'word': 'Congress', 'start': 63, 'end': 71}
One report, from Montana, described an increasingly vocal movement opposed to new coal-fired power plants on the Great Plains.
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99978316, 'index': 5, 'word': 'Montana', 'start': 17, 'end': 24}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9987291, 'index': 22, 'word': 'Great', 'start': 113, 'end': 118}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.99753004, 'index': 23, 'word': 'Plains', 'start': 119, 'end': 125}
The movement includes not only the usual suspects in the environmental community but also conservative and largely Republican ranchers worried about the impact of global warming on their water supply.
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.99972564, 'index': 18, 'word': 'Republican', 'start': 115, 'end': 125}
In addition, The Times reported that a state regulator in Kansas had denied a permit for a large coal-fired power plant because of the global warming gases it would emit.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99886763, 'index': 4, 'word': 'The', 'start': 13, 'end': 16}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.99858755, 'index': 5, 'word': 'Times', 'start': 17, 'end': 22}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99975586, 'index': 12, 'word': 'Kansas', 'start': 58, 'end': 64}
As far as anyone knows, that’s the first time that a power plant has been blocked for that reason alone.
Now it’s Washington’s turn.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.5542361, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Washington', 'start': 9, 'end': 19}
A Senate subcommittee will soon take up a very promising global warming bill written by Joseph Lieberman of Connecticut and John Warner of Virginia — the first step in what could be an arduous legislative journey.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9985142, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Senate', 'start': 2, 'end': 8}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9997709, 'index': 19, 'word': 'Joseph', 'start': 88, 'end': 94}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9997757, 'index': 20, 'word': 'Lie', 'start': 95, 'end': 98}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99955374, 'index': 21, 'word': '##berman', 'start': 98, 'end': 104}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99971175, 'index': 23, 'word': 'Connecticut', 'start': 108, 'end': 119}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9997489, 'index': 25, 'word': 'John', 'start': 124, 'end': 128}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9997664, 'index': 26, 'word': 'Warner', 'start': 129, 'end': 135}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99975806, 'index': 28, 'word': 'Virginia', 'start': 139, 'end': 147}
The bill would place a mandatory, declining cap on emissions from the electric power, manufacturing and transportation sectors of the economy.
It aims to cut total emissions to 63 percent below 2005 levels by 2050, less than many scientists say is necessary but still very ambitious.
The coal industry will try very hard to weaken the bill, and it has assembled a large war chest for that purpose.
Coal accounts for just over half the electricity generated in America and 30 percent of its carbon dioxide emissions.
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9997385, 'index': 11, 'word': 'America', 'start': 62, 'end': 69}
Unless ways can be found to replace coal as an energy source or to capture its emissions, the global warming game is essentially lost.
More than 120 new coal-fired power plants are on the drawing boards in this country.
Of those, only a small percent are likely to be equipped with technologies that could reduce emissions.
The Lieberman-Warner bill makes it clear that coal-fired power plants, new or old, will be forced to meet stiff new emissions targets just like everyone else.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.98497176, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Lie', 'start': 4, 'end': 7}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.5844249, 'index': 3, 'word': '##berman', 'start': 7, 'end': 13}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.94735956, 'index': 5, 'word': 'Warner', 'start': 14, 'end': 20}
Dirty plants, in short, will pay heavily, as they should.
That is the only way to encourage the utilities to find cleaner ways of burning coal and, even better, alternative energy sources.
Until the United States takes the lead, other big emitters — starting with China, which is building the equivalent of one large coal-fired plant every week — will feel no pressure to act.
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99973893, 'index': 3, 'word': 'United', 'start': 10, 'end': 16}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.99932176, 'index': 4, 'word': 'States', 'start': 17, 'end': 23}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99983615, 'index': 16, 'word': 'China', 'start': 75, 'end': 80}
Last of the Reader-Designed Taxi Logos
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.93798196, 'index': 4, 'word': 'Reader', 'start': 12, 'end': 18}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.8726504, 'index': 6, 'word': 'Designed', 'start': 19, 'end': 27}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9671989, 'index': 8, 'word': '##i', 'start': 31, 'end': 32}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.98643357, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Lo', 'start': 33, 'end': 35}
{'entity': 'I-MISC', 'score': 0.9619633, 'index': 10, 'word': '##gos', 'start': 35, 'end': 38}
As part of our series on the new taxi logo at right, we invited readers to submit their own designs.
This is the final set we'll be publishing at the post level, but readers are welcome to continue posting links to their proposals.
From Amanda P.:
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9989134, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Amanda', 'start': 5, 'end': 11}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99666566, 'index': 3, 'word': 'P', 'start': 12, 'end': 13}
Srta.Puri explains his contribution, below: "It's a Spanish-Madrid city taxi turned into a yellow cab, to help foreigners abroad find a taxi."
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99457747, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Sr', 'start': 0, 'end': 2}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.43704063, 'index': 2, 'word': '##ta', 'start': 2, 'end': 4}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99779123, 'index': 4, 'word': 'P', 'start': 5, 'end': 6}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.96162504, 'index': 5, 'word': '##uri', 'start': 6, 'end': 9}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.99815434, 'index': 17, 'word': 'Spanish', 'start': 52, 'end': 59}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.983924, 'index': 19, 'word': 'Madrid', 'start': 60, 'end': 66}
Alistair Hall at We Made This writes, "If they're gonna integrate the NYC logo into a taxi logo, they should just go the whole hog (with the added bonus of being NYC going from A to B).
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9997405, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Alistair', 'start': 0, 'end': 8}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9997598, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Hall', 'start': 9, 'end': 13}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.90904385, 'index': 4, 'word': 'We', 'start': 17, 'end': 19}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.5121935, 'index': 5, 'word': 'Made', 'start': 20, 'end': 24}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.64327556, 'index': 6, 'word': 'This', 'start': 25, 'end': 29}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99324065, 'index': 17, 'word': 'NYC', 'start': 70, 'end': 73}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99486667, 'index': 39, 'word': 'NYC', 'start': 162, 'end': 165}
With hugs and kisses from London.
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99960256, 'index': 7, 'word': 'London', 'start': 26, 'end': 32}
Jennifer Ward of Brooklyn sent us this one:
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9997572, 'index': 1, 'word': 'Jennifer', 'start': 0, 'end': 8}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99968576, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Ward', 'start': 9, 'end': 13}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99781275, 'index': 4, 'word': 'Brooklyn', 'start': 17, 'end': 25}
"Instead of worrying about text so much, why not just make them simple and beautiful?" asks Bobby S. "What if cabs across the city were decorated with different patterns, making cabs something beautiful to look at?"
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9990651, 'index': 21, 'word': 'Bobby', 'start': 92, 'end': 97}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9844601, 'index': 22, 'word': 'S', 'start': 98, 'end': 99}
Here are his proposals:
And lastly, from Michael Condouris, who writes about his design below: "Make it easy to read, incorporate the checker pattern into the X for a little designiness, and you've got something fun, obvious and clear."
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99977624, 'index': 6, 'word': 'Michael', 'start': 17, 'end': 24}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99979126, 'index': 7, 'word': 'Con', 'start': 25, 'end': 28}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.95609087, 'index': 8, 'word': '##do', 'start': 28, 'end': 30}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.76767987, 'index': 10, 'word': '##s', 'start': 33, 'end': 34}
Thanks, everybody.
Facing Possible Expulsion, Lawmaker Will Step Down
HARTFORD, Nov. 13 — The former State Senate minority leader said Tuesday that he would resign from the Senate rather than risk expulsion for asking a trash hauler with reputed ties to organized crime to threaten his granddaughter’s husband, who he claimed had been abusing her.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9947476, 'index': 12, 'word': 'State', 'start': 31, 'end': 36}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.94170076, 'index': 13, 'word': 'Senate', 'start': 37, 'end': 43}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9986766, 'index': 24, 'word': 'Senate', 'start': 103, 'end': 109}
The former leader, Senator Louis C. DeLuca, 74, with his wife, Alice, by his side at a press conference at the Capitol, read haltingly from a statement. “I guess it was almost 17 years ago,” he said, referring to when he was first elected to the Senate.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.999513, 'index': 6, 'word': 'Louis', 'start': 27, 'end': 32}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9980128, 'index': 7, 'word': 'C', 'start': 33, 'end': 34}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99742067, 'index': 8, 'word': '.', 'start': 34, 'end': 35}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99943525, 'index': 9, 'word': 'De', 'start': 36, 'end': 38}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.998656, 'index': 10, 'word': '##L', 'start': 38, 'end': 39}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99633193, 'index': 11, 'word': '##uca', 'start': 39, 'end': 42}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9970829, 'index': 19, 'word': 'Alice', 'start': 63, 'end': 68}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9416599, 'index': 30, 'word': 'Capitol', 'start': 111, 'end': 118}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9979583, 'index': 60, 'word': 'Senate', 'start': 246, 'end': 252}
Then, fighting back tears, he said, “I can’t even get through the first line.”
But he continued. “I harbor no ill will or anger toward those who think poorly of my conduct or my actions that have brought us here today,” said Mr. DeLuca, who had been the Senate Republican leader from 2001 until June, when he stepped down after pleading guilty to a misdemeanor threat charge.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9982874, 'index': 33, 'word': 'De', 'start': 150, 'end': 152}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9889851, 'index': 34, 'word': '##L', 'start': 152, 'end': 153}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.80312866, 'index': 35, 'word': '##uca', 'start': 153, 'end': 156}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9969155, 'index': 41, 'word': 'Senate', 'start': 175, 'end': 181}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.99951756, 'index': 42, 'word': 'Republican', 'start': 182, 'end': 192}
He insisted, however, “I did not — ever — violate the public trust.”
Mr. DeLuca, of Woodbury, was the second senator to resign in the past two years.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9965307, 'index': 3, 'word': 'De', 'start': 4, 'end': 6}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9931964, 'index': 4, 'word': '##L', 'start': 6, 'end': 7}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.84843576, 'index': 5, 'word': '##uca', 'start': 7, 'end': 10}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.97873133, 'index': 8, 'word': 'Wood', 'start': 15, 'end': 19}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.99381673, 'index': 9, 'word': '##bury', 'start': 19, 'end': 23}
Senator Ernest E. Newton II, a Democrat of Bridgeport, resigned a day before pleading guilty in September 2005 to felony charges of bribery, tax evasion and mail fraud.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9994324, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Ernest', 'start': 8, 'end': 14}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9980698, 'index': 3, 'word': 'E', 'start': 15, 'end': 16}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99886423, 'index': 4, 'word': '.', 'start': 16, 'end': 17}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9996901, 'index': 5, 'word': 'Newton', 'start': 18, 'end': 24}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.98365396, 'index': 6, 'word': 'II', 'start': 25, 'end': 27}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9991991, 'index': 9, 'word': 'Democrat', 'start': 31, 'end': 39}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9966579, 'index': 11, 'word': 'Bridge', 'start': 43, 'end': 49}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.9987585, 'index': 12, 'word': '##port', 'start': 49, 'end': 53}
A six-member bipartisan committee that had been considering whether to expel, censure or reprimand Mr. DeLuca was poised to ask the Senate on Tuesday for permission to subpoena audiotapes of the senator’s conversation with an undercover F.B.I. agent who was posing as an associate of James Galante, a trash hauler from Danbury.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9968278, 'index': 29, 'word': 'De', 'start': 103, 'end': 105}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.98862034, 'index': 30, 'word': '##L', 'start': 105, 'end': 106}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.760771, 'index': 31, 'word': '##uca', 'start': 106, 'end': 109}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9985971, 'index': 37, 'word': 'Senate', 'start': 132, 'end': 138}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99767464, 'index': 56, 'word': 'F', 'start': 237, 'end': 238}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9958095, 'index': 58, 'word': 'B', 'start': 239, 'end': 240}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.97157073, 'index': 59, 'word': '.', 'start': 240, 'end': 241}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.9942459, 'index': 60, 'word': 'I', 'start': 241, 'end': 242}
{'entity': 'I-ORG', 'score': 0.7628994, 'index': 61, 'word': '.', 'start': 242, 'end': 243}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99972564, 'index': 70, 'word': 'James', 'start': 284, 'end': 289}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99960816, 'index': 71, 'word': 'Gala', 'start': 290, 'end': 294}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9990202, 'index': 72, 'word': '##nte', 'start': 294, 'end': 297}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.98996997, 'index': 79, 'word': 'Dan', 'start': 319, 'end': 322}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.9940754, 'index': 80, 'word': '##bury', 'start': 322, 'end': 326}
Mr. Galante was one of 29 people named in a federal indictment accusing trash haulers and suspected organized crime figures of conspiring to eliminate competition and drive up prices in Connecticut and New York.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9863005, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Gala', 'start': 4, 'end': 8}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.8096461, 'index': 4, 'word': '##nte', 'start': 8, 'end': 11}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9996976, 'index': 36, 'word': 'Connecticut', 'start': 186, 'end': 197}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9994229, 'index': 38, 'word': 'New', 'start': 202, 'end': 205}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.99942195, 'index': 39, 'word': 'York', 'start': 206, 'end': 210}
In June, Mr. DeLuca admitted asking Mr. Galante to threaten Mark Colella, the husband of his granddaughter Casey Reilly Colella, because the senator suspected him of abusing her.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99634254, 'index': 6, 'word': 'De', 'start': 13, 'end': 15}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9929757, 'index': 7, 'word': '##L', 'start': 15, 'end': 16}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.81759924, 'index': 8, 'word': '##uca', 'start': 16, 'end': 19}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.92805964, 'index': 13, 'word': 'Gala', 'start': 40, 'end': 44}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.6238315, 'index': 14, 'word': '##nte', 'start': 44, 'end': 47}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99976754, 'index': 17, 'word': 'Mark', 'start': 60, 'end': 64}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99924016, 'index': 18, 'word': 'Cole', 'start': 65, 'end': 69}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9982911, 'index': 19, 'word': '##lla', 'start': 69, 'end': 72}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9995614, 'index': 26, 'word': 'Casey', 'start': 107, 'end': 112}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9957244, 'index': 27, 'word': 'Reilly', 'start': 113, 'end': 119}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99832064, 'index': 28, 'word': 'Cole', 'start': 120, 'end': 124}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9573987, 'index': 29, 'word': '##lla', 'start': 124, 'end': 127}
However, the committee discovered that last summer Mrs. Reilly Colella signed a police affidavit saying her husband had never “hit me, pushed me or even threatened to hit me.”
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9991129, 'index': 11, 'word': 'Reilly', 'start': 56, 'end': 62}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9983598, 'index': 12, 'word': 'Cole', 'start': 63, 'end': 67}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.8076595, 'index': 13, 'word': '##lla', 'start': 67, 'end': 70}
Most of Mr. DeLuca’s colleagues had declined to comment publicly on his predicament.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9852496, 'index': 5, 'word': 'De', 'start': 12, 'end': 14}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9711024, 'index': 6, 'word': '##L', 'start': 14, 'end': 15}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.5283398, 'index': 7, 'word': '##uca', 'start': 15, 'end': 18}
But after Mr. DeLuca offered his resignation effective Nov. 30, the Senate president, Donald E. Williams Jr., a Democrat of Brooklyn, Conn., said, “What Senator DeLuca did was wrong.” He also said he was disappointed that the senator remained in office for five months after pleading guilty.
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9885378, 'index': 5, 'word': 'De', 'start': 14, 'end': 16}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9959075, 'index': 6, 'word': '##L', 'start': 16, 'end': 17}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.85980195, 'index': 7, 'word': '##uca', 'start': 17, 'end': 20}
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.9986691, 'index': 17, 'word': 'Senate', 'start': 68, 'end': 74}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.99964374, 'index': 20, 'word': 'Donald', 'start': 86, 'end': 92}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9982529, 'index': 21, 'word': 'E', 'start': 93, 'end': 94}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99831194, 'index': 22, 'word': '.', 'start': 94, 'end': 95}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9996627, 'index': 23, 'word': 'Williams', 'start': 96, 'end': 104}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99904436, 'index': 24, 'word': 'Jr', 'start': 105, 'end': 107}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9991922, 'index': 28, 'word': 'Democrat', 'start': 112, 'end': 120}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9966584, 'index': 30, 'word': 'Brooklyn', 'start': 124, 'end': 132}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.9962542, 'index': 32, 'word': 'Con', 'start': 134, 'end': 137}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.99579865, 'index': 33, 'word': '##n', 'start': 137, 'end': 138}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9961067, 'index': 40, 'word': 'De', 'start': 161, 'end': 163}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99371743, 'index': 41, 'word': '##L', 'start': 163, 'end': 164}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.8590236, 'index': 42, 'word': '##uca', 'start': 164, 'end': 167}
Mr. Williams said that based on the committee’s investigation, it had become clear that Mr. DeLuca’s “wrongful behavior went well beyond what he pled guilty to in June.”
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.997134, 'index': 3, 'word': 'Williams', 'start': 4, 'end': 12}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9983161, 'index': 19, 'word': 'De', 'start': 92, 'end': 94}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9748976, 'index': 20, 'word': '##L', 'start': 94, 'end': 95}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.82819694, 'index': 21, 'word': '##uca', 'start': 95, 'end': 98}
Senator Donald J. DeFronzo, a Democrat of New Britain who was on the bipartisan panel, said, “We wanted the subpoena power because we wanted to afford the senator every opportunity to make his case and let committee members feel comfortable with their vote.”
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9994698, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Donald', 'start': 8, 'end': 14}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.9991239, 'index': 3, 'word': 'J', 'start': 15, 'end': 16}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99897724, 'index': 4, 'word': '.', 'start': 16, 'end': 17}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99965537, 'index': 5, 'word': 'De', 'start': 18, 'end': 20}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99939674, 'index': 6, 'word': '##F', 'start': 20, 'end': 21}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.90568566, 'index': 7, 'word': '##ron', 'start': 21, 'end': 24}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.97865605, 'index': 8, 'word': '##zo', 'start': 24, 'end': 26}
{'entity': 'B-MISC', 'score': 0.9995321, 'index': 11, 'word': 'Democrat', 'start': 30, 'end': 38}
{'entity': 'B-LOC', 'score': 0.99887973, 'index': 13, 'word': 'New', 'start': 42, 'end': 45}
{'entity': 'I-LOC', 'score': 0.99911964, 'index': 14, 'word': 'Britain', 'start': 46, 'end': 53}
The Senate minority leader, John McKinney, a Republican of Southport, said that he did not want to minimize the mistakes Mr. DeLuca had made, but that he hoped the public would remember his 17 years of public service. “Today is a difficult day, and he’s doing what he believes is right for himself and his family,” Mr. McKinney said.
{'entity': 'B-ORG', 'score': 0.99812275, 'index': 2, 'word': 'Senate', 'start': 4, 'end': 10}
{'entity': 'B-PER', 'score': 0.9997292, 'index': 6, 'word': 'John', 'start': 28, 'end': 32}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99969715, 'index': 7, 'word': 'M', 'start': 33, 'end': 34}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99915856, 'index': 8, 'word': '##c', 'start': 34, 'end': 35}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.99917954, 'index': 9, 'word': '##K', 'start': 35, 'end': 36}
{'entity': 'I-PER', 'score': 0.94267756, 'index': 10, 'word': '##inn', 'start': 36, 'end': 39}
