#!/bin/bash
#SBATCH --job-name=data-proc
#SBATCH --partition=gpu-2080ti
#SBATCH --account=ark
#SBATCH --nodes=1
#SBATCH --cpus-per-task=8
#SBATCH --mem=32G
#SBATCH --gres=gpu:1
#SBATCH --time=12:00:00 
#SBATCH --mail-type=ALL
#SBATCH --mail-user=tjung2@uw.edu

# I use source to initialize conda into the right environment.
cat $0
echo "--------------------"

source ~/.bashrc
conda activate ckl

# python run.py --config configs/templama/training/t5_kadapters_yearly_2freeze.json -checkpoint_path outputs/wmtbaseline_full/epoch=0-f1_score=0.151-em_score=0.000.ckpt

# python run.py --config configs/wmt/training/t5_kadapters_yearly_2freeze.json -checkpoint_path outputs/wmtkadapter_2010_2freeze_158_128/epoch=8-f1_score=0.084-em_score=0.000.ckpt

# python preprocess_wmt_train_data.py 2016
# python preprocess_wmt_train_data.py 2017
# python preprocess_wmt_train_data.py 2018

# python run.py --config configs/templama/training/t5_kadapters_soft_full.json -checkpoint_path outputs/wmtkadapter_2010_2freeze_158_128/epoch=8-f1_score=0.084-em_score=0.000.ckpt

# python run.py --config configs/templama/evaluation/t5_baseline_full.json -val_data 2010

# python run.py --config configs/templama/evaluation/t5_kadapters_soft_full.json -val_data 2010

python test.py
--------------------
Read csv: 3.1926909950000004 seconds
decode sentences: 0.003151114999999649 seconds
Create sentences: 0.0012456719999995869 seconds
Run spacy on sentences: 0.4644126530000001 seconds
For Die-Hard Mets Fan, a 1,200-Mile Commute
[(Die-Hard Mets Fan, 'ORG'), (1,200-Mile Commute, 'QUANTITY')]
Most sports fans who have moved away from their hometowns are content to follow their favorite team on cable television or the Internet.
[]
Bobby Lee is not that kind of fan.
[(Bobby Lee, 'PERSON')]
For Mr. Lee, a boyish looking 48-year-old retired New York City firefighter, there is no substitute for being there.
[(Lee, 'PERSON'), (48-year-old, 'DATE'), (New York City, 'GPE')]
So, for nearly every New York Mets homestand over the past four years, Mr. Lee has flown to New York from his adopted home of Kansas City, Mo., to sell cotton candy at the games.
[(New York Mets, 'ORG'), (the past four years, 'DATE'), (Lee, 'PERSON'), (New York, 'GPE'), (Kansas City, 'GPE'), (Mo., 'GPE')]
That's the kind of fan Bobby Lee is.
[(Bobby Lee, 'PERSON')]
Mr. Lee, a compact man with a wry sense of humor, prefers not to call what he does obsessive.
[(Lee, 'PERSON')]
What it is, he says, is a diversion.
[]
When told that leaving a wife and two children behind to travel nearly 1,200 miles to spend as long as two weeks at a time lugging trays of cotton candy up and down Shea Stadium's concrete stairs, all in the pursuit of a few innings of baseball, is a rather unusual pastime, he shrugs.
[(two, 'CARDINAL'), (nearly 1,200 miles, 'QUANTITY'), (as long as two weeks, 'DATE'), (Shea Stadium's, 'FAC')]
"It's my hobby," he said.
[]
Some guys collect coins.
[]
If I wasn't doing this, I wouldn't know what to do with myself in the summer.
[(the summer, 'DATE')]
Mr. Lee's wife, Sue, 50, is herself a Mets fan, which she says helps her to understand her husband's need to be at the games.
[(Lee, 'PERSON'), (Sue, 'PERSON'), (50, 'DATE'), (Mets, 'ORG')]
On their first date 22 years ago, she said, Mr. Lee gave her a Keith Hernandez baseball card.
[(their first date 22 years ago, 'DATE'), (Lee, 'PERSON'), (Keith Hernandez, 'GPE')]
Luckily, Hernandez, the first baseman on the Mets" 1986 World Series championship team, was her favorite player.
[(Hernandez, 'ORG'), (Mets, 'ORG'), (1986, 'DATE'), (World Series, 'EVENT')]
From then on, the Mets became a crucial element of their relationship.
[(Mets, 'ORG')]
Part of the agreement the couple had when the family moved in 2003 to the Kansas City suburb of Oak Grove from Rockland County, was that Mr. Lee could come back to town for Mets games.
[(2003, 'DATE'), (Kansas City, 'GPE'), (Oak Grove, 'GPE'), (Rockland County, 'GPE'), (Lee, 'PERSON'), (Mets, 'ORG')]
"I asked this native New Yorker to move to the Midwest for my job," said Mrs. Lee, who works for a company that publishes agricultural books and pamphlets.
[(New Yorker, 'ORG'), (Midwest, 'LOC'), (Lee, 'PERSON')]
He made a pretty big sacrifice.
[]
In Mr. Lee's version, the conversation went something like this: "She said, "I want to move to the Midwest," and I said, "O.K., but I want to keep my seniority," " he said, referring to the vending position he has held for decades.
[(Lee, 'PERSON'), (Midwest, 'LOC'), (decades, 'DATE')]
While Mr. Lee is away for much of the summer, Mrs. Lee juggles work, which includes frequent travel, and handles extracurricular duties for the couple's two daughters, ages 10 and 13.
[(Lee, 'PERSON'), (the summer, 'DATE'), (Lee, 'PERSON'), (two, 'CARDINAL'), (ages 10 and 13, 'DATE')]
"At work, I have the Mets" schedule printed out between the telephone and the laptop," she said.
[(Mets, 'ORG')]
I literally work around the Mets schedule.
[(Mets, 'ORG')]
As unusual as the Lees" story seems, it was in some ways fated.
[(Lees, 'ORG')]
Mr. Lee's grandfather was an usher at Yankee Stadium for 40 years, starting in 1935 - the year after Babe Ruth left the Yankees, but in an era that included the playing days of Gehrig, DiMaggio, Berra, Mantle, Maris and 16 world championships.
[(Lee, 'PERSON'), (Yankee Stadium, 'FAC'), (40 years, 'DATE'), (1935 - the year, 'DATE'), (Babe Ruth, 'PERSON'), (Yankees, 'ORG'), (the playing days, 'DATE'), (Berra, 'GPE'), (Mantle, 'GPE'), (Maris, 'PERSON'), (16, 'CARDINAL')]
Mr. Lee's father worked as an usher as well, but at the Polo Grounds, which meant he grew up hearing stories about the heroics of the New York Giants" star player Willie Mays.
[(Lee, 'PERSON'), (the Polo Grounds, 'FAC'), (the New York Giants, 'ORG'), (Willie Mays, 'PERSON')]
Mr. Lee's older brother took up the trade, too, albeit briefly, at Shea Stadium, a few miles from the Queens home where the family had moved by that time.
[(Lee, 'PERSON'), (Shea Stadium, 'FAC'), (a few miles, 'QUANTITY'), (Queens, 'GPE')]
Soon after, at 16, Mr. Lee, took up the family business as well.
[(16, 'CARDINAL'), (Lee, 'PERSON')]
As a vendor at Shea, he sold orangeade for 35 cents a cup during baseball season, and hot chocolate during football season.
[(Shea, 'ORG'), (35 cents, 'MONEY')]
During his two years at Queensborough Community College, and then through jobs as a telephone sales representative, a mail carrier and 20 years as a firefighter, Mr. Lee worked at Shea during his off hours, his vending uniforms as subject to the trends of the time as the uniforms worn by the players.
[(his two years, 'DATE'), (Queensborough Community College, 'ORG'), (20 years, 'DATE'), (Lee, 'PERSON'), (Shea, 'ORG'), (his off hours, 'TIME')]
Because the Mets were such a thoroughly rotten club during much of the 1970s and into the early 1980s, the team attracted few fans, which made it particularly tough on vendors, who were sent home if there were not enough people in the stands.
[(Mets, 'ORG'), (the 1970s, 'DATE'), (the early 1980s, 'DATE')]
"I've wasted a lot of time when there were more workers than fans, when you could yell across the stadium and hear an echo," he said.
[]
The arrival of Darryl Strawberry, Dwight Gooden and Hernandez and others made the team a winner, but Mr. Lee acknowledged that selling cotton candy at Shea Stadium might actually be the worst way for a Mets fan to watch a game.
[(Darryl Strawberry, 'PERSON'), (Dwight Gooden, 'PERSON'), (Hernandez, 'ORG'), (Lee, 'PERSON'), (Shea Stadium, 'FAC'), (Mets, 'ORG')]
"If you want to make money, you don't watch the games," he said.
[]
There are times when I leave that I don't even know the score.
[]
My back is to the field the whole time.
[]
Most of the time, he said, he can guess what is going on by the crowd's reactions.
[]
But when a star steps up to the plate, particularly in a critical situation, he turns around and watches along with everyone else because shouting "Cotton candy!
[(Cotton, 'PERSON')]
Get your cotton candy here!" will only irritate people during a game's tense moments.
[]
"Everything's got to stop for those few minutes when those players are up," he said, mentioning the former Mets player Mike Piazza, along with the all-time home run leader Barry Bonds and the former St. Louis Cardinals slugger Mark McGwire.
[(Everything's, 'ORG'), (those few minutes, 'TIME'), (Mets, 'ORG'), (Mike Piazza, 'PERSON'), (Barry Bonds, 'PERSON'), (St. Louis Cardinals, 'ORG'), (Mark McGwire, 'PERSON')]
Mr. Lee says he travels to about 60 of the Mets" 81 home games each season, and sells about 300 sticks of cotton candy on an average night.
[(Lee, 'PERSON'), (about 60, 'CARDINAL'), (81, 'CARDINAL'), (each season, 'DATE'), (about 300, 'CARDINAL'), (an average night, 'TIME')]
On a busy night, he sells as many as 700, which cost $4 apiece.
[(a busy night, 'TIME'), (as many as 700, 'CARDINAL'), (4, 'MONEY')]
He figures that he sells at least 18,000 sticks of cotton candy a season, and has the calluses on the print of each thumb to prove it.
[(at least 18,000, 'CARDINAL')]
Among vendors, commission rates vary according to individuals and are a closely held secret.
[]
His, he said, is between 10 and 16 percent.
[(10 and 16 percent, 'PERCENT')]
His mother still lives in the family's house near Shea, and during homestands he stays there.
[(Shea, 'ORG')]
On his way back to Missouri, he fills a knapsack with cotton candy for his daughters.
[(Missouri, 'GPE')]
Occasionally, he said, he'll see friends from his days at Holy Cross High School, in the Flushing section of Queens, at Mets games.
[(Holy Cross High School, 'ORG'), (Flushing, 'NORP'), (Queens, 'GPE'), (Mets, 'ORG')]
They'll look at his face, read his name tag, and ask, "Hey, you still work here?"
[]

[]
Dangers of a Turbocharged Economy
[]
IT’S Labor Day weekend, so let’s talk about labor.
[(Labor Day weekend, 'DATE')]
Capital absorbs our attention most of the other 364 days of the year.
[(the other 364 days of the year, 'DATE')]
Around 140 million people are employed in the United States.
[(Around 140 million, 'CARDINAL'), (the United States, 'GPE')]
They are engaged in work like governing, manufacturing, health care providing, retailing and researching (as well as suing).
[]
This gigantic army of laborers, argues Robert B. Reich, has morphed into a nation of consumers and investors, rather than citizens. “Supercapitalism” (Knopf, $25), his 11th book, seeks to explain why this supercharged economic system is a civic problem, and what can be done about it.
[(Robert B. Reich, 'PERSON'), (Knopf, 'ORG'), (25, 'MONEY'), (11th, 'ORDINAL')]
Nor does he harp on lax government regulation of credit and mortgage practices.
[]
On the contrary, he criticizes many of the usual liberal fixes directed at the “excesses of the market.” His book is smart and compelling, if ultimately toothless.
[]
Born in 1946, Mr. Reich served as labor secretary under President Bill Clinton, the avatar of the have-it-all baby boom generation.
[(1946, 'DATE'), (Reich, 'PERSON'), (Bill Clinton, 'PERSON')]
Equally significant, though, is that Mr. Reich’s government service dates back to the administrations of Gerald R. Ford and Jimmy Carter — that is, to the 1970s, the decade when America’s immediate postwar economy, a middle-class bonanza like no other, began to give way to today’s upper-class bacchanalia.
[(Gerald R. Ford, 'PERSON'), (Jimmy Carter, 'PERSON'), (the 1970s, 'DATE'), (the decade, 'DATE')]
It was during what Mr. Reich aptly calls the Not Quite Golden Age, from 1945 to 1975, that America prospered, income inequality fell and most people trusted in government.
[(Reich, 'PERSON'), (from 1945 to, 'DATE'), (1975, 'DATE'), (America, 'GPE')]
Then, thanks to technologies like shipping containers and the Web, companies suddenly confronted brutal competition.
[]
After that, there was no going back.
[]
Consumers got more choice and lower prices, while the people on Main Street became investors.
[(Main Street, 'FAC')]
Together, newly powerful shoppers and shareholders of this supercapitalism drove a decline in labor unions and a frenzy by corporations desperate to buy some market advantage in Washington.
[(Washington, 'GPE')]
“You and I are complicit,” Mr. Reich writes.
[(complicit,”, 'ORG'), (Reich, 'PERSON')]
Our “great deals” are somebody else’s lower pay and some corporation’s lobbying.
[]
We are hypocrites, too, he says.
[]
One of the book’s examples of consumers’ hypocrisy has to do with canned tuna.
[(One, 'CARDINAL'), (consumers’, 'GPE')]
J. W. Connolly, former president of Heinz U.S.A., which was the parent company of StarKist, explains that “consumers wanted a dolphin-safe product,” but “if there was a dolphin-safe can of tuna next to a regular can, people chose the cheaper product.
[(J. W. Connolly, 'PERSON'), (Heinz U.S.A., 'ORG'), (StarKist, 'ORG')]
Even if the difference was a penny.” The company terminated its higher-cost effort to protect dolphins.
[]
After all, it’s a business, beholden to consumers and shareholders.
[(beholden, 'GPE')]
With such vignettes culled from the news media, Mr. Reich disembowels proponents of corporate “social responsibility.” He shows that companies like Wal-Mart are operating legally yet being shamed into incurring social costs that their competitors are not.
[(Reich, 'PERSON'), (Wal-Mart, 'ORG')]
Critics’ campaigns are a misleading diversion, he argues, because they confuse businesses with what they can never be: public interest bodies.
[(Critics’, 'PRODUCT')]
Public-relations skirmishes are no substitute for democracy.
[]
The ritual scolding of corporations in front of Congressional committees, Mr. Reich says, goes hand in hand with Congress’s failure to pass follow-up laws that reward businesses for safeguarding the environment or walking away from deals with serial human rights abusers.
[(Reich, 'PERSON'), (Congress’s, 'ORG')]
Washington is all about the money, he writes.
[(Washington, 'GPE')]
In 2005, the Census Bureau listed seven suburban counties around the capital as among the 20 richest in the country.
[(2005, 'DATE'), (the Census Bureau, 'ORG'), (seven, 'CARDINAL'), (20, 'CARDINAL')]
And it’s not just Republicans cashing in on their service. “Upon leaving office,” he notes, “more than half of the senior officials in the Clinton administration became corporate lobbyists.”
[(Republicans, 'NORP'), (office,”, 'ORG'), (“more than half, 'CARDINAL'), (Clinton, 'PERSON')]
Would-be analysts of this trend, Mr. Reich says, have it backward; government is not historically bigger now, relative to gross domestic product, and politicians are not more corrupt.
[(Reich, 'PERSON')]
Rather, market competition is greater, which means that public policy contests — over organic labeling, for example — have more than ever become just brawls among business rivals.
[]
Here, however, we arrive at a cul-de-sac.
[]
Mr. Reich argues that the “most effective thing reformers could do is to reduce the effects of corporate money on politics and enhance the voices of citizens.” But he also writes of the lock that corporations have and how “the system cannot repair itself from the inside.”
[(Reich, 'PERSON')]
So he opts for consciousness-raising.
[]
The public and the media, he writes, must understand the obscured truths laid bare in his book and demand change.
[]
In passing, Mr. Reich comes out in favor of decoupling health insurance from employers and raising the minimum wage to about half the average worker’s wage.
[(Reich, 'PERSON'), (about half, 'CARDINAL')]
He mentions runaway C.E.O. pay but offers no prescriptions.
[(C.E.O., 'ORG')]
Capping executive compensation is liable to be rejected as un-American, which it is.
[(Capping, 'ORG'), (un-American, 'NORP')]
So here’s my suggestion: a legally binding maximum on C.E.O. multiples of their own workers’ salaries.
[(C.E.O., 'ORG')]
Let’s pick a multiple of 300, well above the historical average.
[(300, 'CARDINAL')]
If chief executives want to be paid hundreds of millions, and boards comply, no problem; the C.E.O.’s task would be to figure out how to pay the company’s lowest worker hundreds of thousands.
That would be supercapitalism.
[]
Chief executives could devote their formidable talents to raising the skills and living standards of loyal work forces and avoiding the huge self-imposed costs of labor turnover, rather than gaming quarterly reports.
[(quarterly, 'DATE')]
Shareholders would remain empowered to invest or divest based on performance.
[]
A lot of American businesses are already well in line with the proposed pay multiple.
[(American, 'NORP')]
Companies that insist that they could never compete under the mandated guideline would have an option: look abroad for a cheaper C.E.O.
[(C.E.O., 'ORG')]
To provide an incentive, Congress could enact one of Mr. Reich’s best-argued proposals: elimination of the corporate income tax.
[(Congress, 'ORG'), (one, 'CARDINAL')]
But only for companies in compliance with the pay-scale multiple.
[]
Happy Labor Day.
[(Labor Day, 'DATE')]

[]
6 - Eleven current or former public officials, including two members of the State Assembly, were charged Thursday with taking thousands of dollars in bribes in exchange for promising municipal business to undercover officers posing as insurance brokers in the latest federal probe into New Jersey's rampant political corruption.
[(two, 'CARDINAL'), (the State Assembly, 'ORG'), (Thursday, 'DATE'), (thousands of dollars, 'MONEY'), (New Jersey's, 'GPE')]
The officials, and a man affiliated with one of them, were rounded up by agents with the Federal Bureau of Investigation early Thursday morning and appeared before a judge in Federal District Court here by afternoon.
[(one, 'CARDINAL'), (the Federal Bureau of Investigation, 'ORG'), (Thursday, 'DATE'), (morning, 'TIME'), (Federal District Court, 'ORG'), (afternoon, 'TIME')]
The arrests culminated an 18-month investigation in which an undercover agent and cooperating witnesses posed as insurance brokers and traded wads of cash ranging from $1,500 to $17,500 for assurances of votes on school boards and city councils.
[(18-month, 'DATE'), ($1,500 to $17,500, 'MONEY')]
The investigation initially focused on the Pleasantville Board of Education, which runs a tiny, impoverished school district near Atlantic City.
[(the Pleasantville Board of Education, 'ORG'), (Atlantic City, 'GPE')]
With 13 superintendents in the last 10 years, the district has been plagued by turmoil and is now working with a state-appointed monitor.
[(13, 'CARDINAL'), (the last 10 years, 'DATE')]
But then, unexpectedly, Pleasantville officials led federal investigators on what Christopher J. Christie, the United States attorney for New Jersey, described at a news conference here as a "corruption tour" of New Jersey by referring the fake insurers to other parts of the state.
[(Pleasantville, 'GPE'), (Christopher J. Christie, 'PERSON'), (United States, 'GPE'), (New Jersey, 'GPE'), (New Jersey, 'GPE')]
That tour, prosecutors said, ranged 125 miles north to Passaic and Paterson, two gritty towns just outside New York City known for rough politics, as well as to Newark and Orange.
[(125 miles, 'QUANTITY'), (Paterson, 'PERSON'), (two, 'CARDINAL'), (New York City, 'GPE'), (Newark, 'GPE'), (Orange, 'GPE')]
And the way it transpired resembled the New Jersey of Hollywood as meetings unfolded in parked cars, rest stops on the Garden State Parkway, restaurants and hotels.
[(the New Jersey of, 'ORG'), (Hollywood, 'GPE'), (the Garden State Parkway, 'FAC')]
The arrests are the latest example of how the state's roster of elected and appointed officials has come, at times, to resemble a police blotter.
[]
Two powerful Democratic veterans - Sharpe James, the former mayor of Newark, and Wayne R. Bryant, a state senator from Camden - were indicted earlier this year, and State Senator Joseph Coniglio, a Democrat of Bergen County, has been notified by prosecutors that he is the target of a corruption investigation.
[(Two, 'CARDINAL'), (Democratic, 'NORP'), (Newark, 'GPE'), (Wayne R. Bryant, 'PERSON'), (Camden, 'GPE'), (earlier this year, 'DATE'), (State, 'ORG'), (Joseph Coniglio, 'PERSON'), (Democrat, 'NORP'), (Bergen County, 'GPE')]
But even Mr. Christie said that he was stunned by the business-as-usual boldness uncovered in the most recent investigation, which the F.B.I. dubbed Operation Broken Boards.
[(Christie, 'PERSON')]
Mr. Christie noted that one of those charged, Assemblyman Mims Hackett Jr., is the chairman of the State Government Committee, which is responsible for government rules and oversight, including ethics legislation.
[(Christie, 'PERSON'), (one, 'CARDINAL'), (Mims Hackett Jr., 'PERSON'), (the State Government Committee, 'ORG')]
"It's been six years doing this job, and I thought I could no longer be surprised by a combination of brazenness, arrogance and stupidity," Mr. Christie said.
[(six years, 'DATE'), (Christie, 'PERSON')]
But the people elected in this state continue to defy description.
[]
Along with Mr. Hackett, who is also the mayor of Orange, the highest-ranking person arrested was Assemblyman Alfred E. Steele, who is also a Baptist minister and an undersheriff in Passaic County.
[(Hackett, 'PERSON'), (Orange, 'ORG'), (Alfred E. Steele, 'PERSON'), (Baptist, 'PRODUCT'), (Passaic County, 'GPE')]
Both hold leadership posts in the Democratic-controlled Assembly.
[(Democratic, 'NORP'), (Assembly, 'ORG')]
Federal investigators also arrested Mayor Samuel Rivera of Passaic, who resigned Thursday from a committee of mayors supporting Senator Hillary Rodham Clinton's presidential bid.
[(Samuel Rivera, 'PERSON'), (Thursday, 'DATE'), (Hillary Rodham Clinton's, 'PERSON')]
Mr. Rivera, a former police officer in both New Jersey and Puerto Rico, has had a variety of run-ins with law enforcement, including domestic violence charges filed by his daughter in 2004 that were later dropped; charges in 2002 of making terroristic threats against a boxer who had gone to the home of a woman Mr. Rivera later married (also dropped); and a 2003 assault conviction for yelling obscenities at a woman and pushing her.
[(Rivera, 'PERSON'), (New Jersey, 'GPE'), (Puerto Rico, 'GPE'), (2004, 'DATE'), (2002, 'DATE'), (Rivera, 'PERSON'), (2003, 'DATE')]
In 1966, a 20-year-old Mr. Rivera, who was working as a security guard, killed his brother-in-law in what was ruled an accidental shooting.
[(1966, 'DATE'), (20-year-old, 'DATE'), (Rivera, 'PERSON')]
And then there was Keith O. Reid, chief of staff to the president of the Newark Municipal Council, who told the undercover investigators that he was the "offensive coordinator" in the city and could make even the quarterbacks get in line.
[(Keith O. Reid, 'PERSON'), (the Newark Municipal Council, 'ORG')]
"So, therefore, I get to say, "That's not the play we're running," " Mr. Reid told the agents, according to court records.
[(Reid, 'PERSON')]
This is the play we're running.
[]
As for those arrested, the general response to reporters" questions at the federal courthouse in Trenton was no comment.
[(Trenton, 'GPE')]
Mr. Steele even ran away, literally, from hordes of reporters chasing him through downtown Trenton, causing rush-hour traffic to halt.
[(Steele, 'PERSON'), (Trenton, 'GPE')]
One person who did say a few things, though, was Mr. Rivera, who suggested in Spanish that Hispanics had always been unfairly targeted.
[(One, 'CARDINAL'), (Rivera, 'PERSON'), (Spanish, 'NORP'), (Hispanics, 'NORP')]
"Siempre," Mr. Rivera said, which means "always," before adding in English later, "I'll have my day in court."
[(Siempre, 'PERSON'), (Rivera, 'PERSON'), (English, 'LANGUAGE')]
The arrests come two days after Gov. Jon S. Corzine signed a package of ethics bills limiting the ability of state lawmakers to hold local posts, which critics say has led to much corruption.
[(two days, 'DATE'), (Jon S. Corzine, 'PERSON')]
They also coincide with the state's Democratic convention, being held in Atlantic City, prompting renewed accusations that Mr. Christie, an ambitious Republican who is mentioned as a likely candidate for governor in 2009, factors politics into the timing of his announcements.
[(Democratic, 'NORP'), (Atlantic City, 'GPE'), (Christie, 'PERSON'), (Republican, 'NORP'), (2009, 'DATE')]
Mr. Christie denied that, as he has at every news conference announcing arrests related to political corruption.
[(Christie, 'PERSON')]
He noted that one of the key players arrested, Jonathan Soto, a former city councilman in Passaic, was a Republican, and insisted that law enforcement considerations alone determined the timing of arrests.
[(Jonathan Soto, 'PERSON'), (Passaic, 'ORG'), (Republican, 'NORP')]
"We never consider politics in those considerations," he said.
[]
It's an old song by people who are trying to defend criminals.
[]
The complaints are based, in part, on hundreds of tape-recorded and videotaped encounters - including some as recent as last week - during which the officials are accused of boasting that they could use their positions to help get insurance and roofing contracts for the undercover agents.
[(hundreds, 'CARDINAL'), (last week, 'DATE')]
And in both Pleasantville and Passaic, they delivered on their promises, as the school board and City Council passed resolutions helpful to the fictitious insurance business, the complaints say.
[(Pleasantville, 'GPE'), (City Council, 'ORG')]
Indeed, Mr. Rivera, in exchange for $5,000, declared in an expletive-laced claim on Aug. 29, according to the complaints: "I make the decision.
[(Rivera, 'PERSON'), (5,000, 'MONEY'), (Aug. 29, 'DATE')]
And believe me, I've got the four votes on the Council.
[(four, 'CARDINAL'), (Council, 'ORG')]
At times, some of those arrested joked about the impropriety of their actions.
[]
Jaysan Adams, a former president of the Pleasantville Board of Education, told a cooperating witness that they would either "get this job together or go to jail together."
[(Jaysan Adams, 'PERSON'), (the Pleasantville Board of Education, 'ORG')]
The other men arrested are Marcellus Jackson, of the Passaic City Council; James Pressley, Rafael Velez and James T. McCormick, of the Pleasantville School Board; Maurice Callaway, a former member of the Pleasantville School Board; and Louis Mister of Pleasantville, an associate of Mr. Callaway's.
[(Marcellus Jackson, 'PERSON'), (the Passaic City Council, 'ORG'), (James Pressley, 'PERSON'), (Rafael Velez, 'PERSON'), (James T. McCormick, 'PERSON'), (the Pleasantville School Board, 'ORG'), (Maurice Callaway, 'PERSON'), (the Pleasantville School Board, 'ORG'), (Louis Mister, 'PERSON'), (Pleasantville, 'GPE'), (Callaway, 'PERSON')]
As news of the arrests spread in the places affected, many residents, so cynical about government officials, said they were not surprised.
[]
Others, meanwhile, wondered whether those accused were inflating their own power to enrich themselves.
[]
In Newark, for instance, some local officials said it was unclear how Mr. Reid, the chief of staff to Mildred Crump, the Municipal Council president, could influence the Council, since her job is largely ceremonial.
[(Newark, 'GPE'), (Reid, 'PERSON'), (the Municipal Council, 'ORG'), (Council, 'ORG')]
When asked Thursday about the charges, Ms. Crump said: "To tell you the truth, I don't believe it.
[(Thursday, 'DATE'), (Crump, 'PERSON')]
I'm shocked.
[]
Then, as tears welled up, she added, "Don't make me cry."
[]
Reporting was contributed by Jon Hurdle in Pleasantville, Andrew Jacobs in Newark, Nate Schweber in Passaic and John Sullivan in New York.
[(Jon Hurdle, 'PERSON'), (Pleasantville, 'GPE'), (Andrew Jacobs, 'PERSON'), (Newark, 'GPE'), (Passaic, 'ORG'), (John Sullivan, 'PERSON'), (New York, 'GPE')]

[]
Pitching Prospect Slipped Onto Yankees" Radar
[(Radar, 'PRODUCT')]
In the 1980s, when Damon Oppenheimer was a catcher at the University of Southern California, the Trojans’ players knew the story of Fred Lynn.
[(the 1980s, 'DATE'), (Oppenheimer, 'ORG'), (the University of Southern California, 'ORG'), (Fred Lynn, 'PERSON')]
A first-team all-American as a sophomore, Lynn did not repeat his success as a junior and slipped out of the first round of the 1973 draft.
[(first, 'ORDINAL'), (all-American, 'NORP'), (Lynn, 'PERSON'), (first, 'ORDINAL'), (1973, 'DATE')]
“Boston took him in the second round, and two years later he was in the big leagues as the rookie of the year,” Oppenheimer said. “That was a story we always heard about.
[(second, 'ORDINAL'), (two years later, 'DATE')]
We’ve just always tried to remember that and think about the whole career of a guy.”
[(guy.”, 'PERSON')]
Oppenheimer is the Yankees’ scouting director now, and Lynn’s tale was instructive in deciding whom to take with the Yankees’ first-round pick in last summer’s draft.
[(Oppenheimer, 'ORG'), (Yankees’, 'PRODUCT'), (Yankees’ first-round, 'DATE')]
Ian Kennedy, a U.S.C. right-hander, had slumped to a 5-7 record and a 3.90 earned run average as a junior.
[(Ian Kennedy, 'PERSON'), (5, 'CARDINAL'), (3.90, 'CARDINAL')]
But various publications had named him a first-team all-American as a sophomore, and that was the pitcher Oppenheimer wanted.
[(first, 'ORDINAL'), (all-American, 'NORP'), (Oppenheimer, 'ORG')]
So when the Yankees’ turn came with the 21st overall pick in 2006, Oppenheimer chose Kennedy and let Brian Cashman, the general manager, work out a $2.25 million bonus with Kennedy’s agent, Scott Boras.
[(21st, 'ORDINAL'), (2006, 'DATE'), (Oppenheimer, 'ORG'), (Kennedy, 'PERSON'), (Brian Cashman, 'PERSON'), ($2.25 million, 'MONEY'), (Kennedy’s, 'NORP'), (Scott Boras, 'PERSON')]
It seems clear now that history guided Oppenheimer well.
[(Oppenheimer, 'ORG')]
Like Lynn, Kennedy reached the majors in September of the year after he was drafted.
[(Lynn, 'PERSON'), (Kennedy, 'PERSON'), (September of the year, 'DATE')]
Lynn went on to win the Rookie of the Year and Most Valuable Player awards while leading the Red Sox to the 1975 World Series.
[(Lynn, 'PERSON'), (Rookie, 'PERSON'), (the Year and Most Valuable Player, 'EVENT'), (the Red Sox, 'ORG'), (the 1975 World Series, 'EVENT')]
The Yankees would settle for less from Kennedy, who has already exceeded expectations.
[(Yankees, 'ORG'), (Kennedy, 'PERSON')]
Kennedy makes his second major league start tonight in Kansas City after beating Tampa Bay with seven strong innings last Saturday.
[(Kennedy, 'PERSON'), (tonight, 'TIME'), (Kansas City, 'GPE'), (Tampa, 'GPE'), (seven, 'CARDINAL'), (last Saturday, 'DATE')]
Like Joba Chamberlain, who was taken with the Yankees’ next pick in 2006, Kennedy climbed three minor league levels to reach the Yankees this season.
[(Joba Chamberlain, 'PERSON'), (Yankees’, 'PRODUCT'), (2006, 'DATE'), (Kennedy, 'PERSON'), (three, 'CARDINAL'), (Yankees, 'ORG'), (this season, 'DATE')]
“Getting to the big leagues and staying in the big leagues are very different things,” Oppenheimer said. “He’s a kid.
[(Oppenheimer, 'ORG'), (“He’s, 'PERSON')]
When you drafted him, you could see him sticking in the big leagues.
[]
But getting there so soon is beyond my wildest dreams, for sure.”
[]
As proof, the Yankees long ago gave Kennedy permission to schedule his wedding for Oct. 6.
[(Yankees, 'ORG'), (Kennedy, 'PERSON'), (Oct. 6, 'DATE')]
The minor league season is over by then, but the major league playoffs are just starting.
[]
The date falls on a day off during the division series, and the wedding is being held in St. Louis, the hometown of Kennedy’s fiancée, the U.S.C. basketball player Allison Jaskowiak.
[(a day, 'DATE'), (St. Louis, 'GPE'), (Kennedy’s, 'NORP'), (Allison Jaskowiak, 'PERSON')]
Kennedy does not seem to know what to root for.
[(Kennedy, 'PERSON')]
“There’s only been two or three September call-ups to actually participate in the playoffs, right?
[(two or three September, 'DATE')]
Like Francisco Rodríguez?” Kennedy said, hopefully, on Wednesday. “I try not to think about it.
[(Francisco Rodríguez?” Kennedy, 'PERSON'), (Wednesday, 'DATE')]
She might get upset.”
[]
By the wedding date, Kennedy could be a crucial contributor the way Rodríguez was for the Angels in 2002.
[(Kennedy, 'PERSON'), (Rodríguez, 'ORG'), (Angels, 'ORG'), (2002, 'DATE')]
The Yankees, who hold a three-game lead in the American League wild-card race, could fit him on the roster.
[(Yankees, 'ORG'), (three, 'CARDINAL'), (American League, 'ORG')]
Of course, nobody knows if Kennedy will fade like other rookies who pitched well in their debuts this season, like Chase Wright, Matt DeSalvo and Tyler Clippard.
[(Kennedy, 'PERSON'), (this season, 'DATE'), (Chase Wright, 'PERSON'), (Matt DeSalvo, 'PERSON'), (Tyler Clippard, 'PERSON')]
Phil Hughes and Chamberlain have come closer to sustained success, and Kennedy is a prospect in their category.
[(Phil Hughes, 'PERSON'), (Chamberlain, 'PERSON'), (Kennedy, 'PERSON')]
Kennedy, 22, went 12-3 in the minors and earned his promotion when the Yankees dropped Mike Mussina from the rotation.
[(Kennedy, 'PERSON'), (22, 'DATE'), (12, 'CARDINAL'), (Yankees, 'ORG'), (Mike Mussina, 'PERSON')]
Kennedy has been compared with Mussina; each commands the low fastball at his best.
[(Kennedy, 'PERSON'), (Mussina, 'GPE')]
But Kennedy’s top off-speed pitch is the changeup, with his curveball still developing, and he is short for a right-handed pitcher.
[(Kennedy’s, 'NORP')]
“For a guy who’s right around six feet, he still gets a good plane on his fastball; it’s all downhill,” Oppenheimer said. “It seems kind of strange, but he gets way out on his front side, so it seems like he’s closer to the plate.
[(around six feet, 'QUANTITY'), (“It, 'ORG')]
That creates some deception.”
[]
To Jeff Clement, who made his debut for the Seattle Mariners on Tuesday, Kennedy’s quick rise was predictable.
[(Jeff Clement, 'PERSON'), (the Seattle Mariners, 'ORG'), (Tuesday, 'DATE'), (Kennedy’s, 'ORG')]
Clement was Kennedy’s catcher at U.S.C. in 2005, when he went 12-2 and was named pitcher of the year in the Pacific-10 Conference.
[(2005, 'DATE'), (12, 'CARDINAL'), (the year, 'DATE')]
“Off the field, he’s easy to get along with,” Clement said. “But when he gets on the mound, he competes like no one else I’ve ever caught.”
[]
Clement mentioned Kennedy’s performance as a freshman on a team trip to Cuba.
[(Kennedy’s, 'NORP'), (Cuba, 'GPE')]
With one out, Kennedy loaded the bases with walks and a broken-bat single.
[(one, 'CARDINAL'), (Kennedy, 'PERSON')]
But he struck out the next two Cuban players to strand the runners.
[(two, 'CARDINAL'), (Cuban, 'NORP')]
“He punched out the next two guys like it was nothing,” Clement said. “So I knew he had the mentality to go out and get after it.”
[(two, 'CARDINAL'), (“So, 'ORG'), (it.”, 'ORG')]
Oppenheimer said the Yankees scouted almost all of Kennedy’s games in his first two college seasons, although they were not always there to see him.
[(Oppenheimer, 'ORG'), (Yankees, 'ORG'), (Kennedy’s, 'NORP'), (first, 'ORDINAL')]
Kennedy also stood out when he pitched for Team U.S.A. against hitters with wood bats.
[(Kennedy, 'PERSON'), (Team U.S.A., 'ORG')]
When Kennedy slipped as a junior, Oppenheimer noticed that he did not seem as comfortable with his catcher as he had with Clement.
[(Kennedy, 'PERSON'), (Oppenheimer, 'ORG')]
The Mariners had drafted Clement third over all the previous June, and Kennedy might have gone that high if he had been eligible.
[(Mariners, 'ORG'), (Clement, 'GPE'), (third, 'ORDINAL'), (all the previous June, 'DATE'), (Kennedy, 'PERSON')]
“If he would have had a year in ’06 like he had in ’05, he would have been a top-five pick, easily,” Clement said.
[(a year, 'DATE'), (five, 'CARDINAL'), (easily,” Clement, 'ORG')]
Kennedy said he put too much pressure on himself to carry the team as a junior.
[(Kennedy, 'PERSON')]
He has no other explanation for the slump that indirectly landed him with the Yankees.
[(Yankees, 'ORG')]
“The only thing I can think of is I failed a couple of times, and I had never really failed before,” Kennedy said. “Even in my losses in college, I didn’t give up a lot of runs, we just lost.
[(Kennedy, 'PERSON')]
Just failing, I didn’t know how to deal with it.
[]
Now I’ve dealt with that and I’ve had success again, and I know how to bounce back from it.”
[(it.”, 'ORG')]
The Yankees have surrounded Kennedy with a support system that includes his Class AAA pitching coach, Dave Eiland, and Chamberlain, who said he considered Kennedy a brother.
[(Yankees, 'ORG'), (Kennedy, 'PERSON'), (AAA, 'ORG'), (Dave Eiland, 'PERSON'), (Chamberlain, 'PERSON'), (Kennedy, 'PERSON')]
Kennedy is inquisitive, asking detailed questions of coaches and teammates, and he said that before tonight’s start, he would ask the veterans how to approach a young team like the Royals.
[(Kennedy, 'PERSON'), (Royals, 'NORP')]
“He just has a great feel for the game,” Eiland said. “The way he watches, he’s always trying to learn and absorb as much as he can.
[(Eiland, 'ORG')]
You tell him something, he looks you right in the eye, and you can tell he’s listening.”
[]
With eyes wide open, Kennedy is learning on the job for a team that never expected to count on him so soon.
[(Kennedy, 'PERSON')]

[]
ABC Reopens Investigation, Again Wary of a Reporter
[(ABC Reopens Investigation, 'ORG')]
ABC News said yesterday that it would begin a second investigation into more than five years of news reports that relied on information from a consultant, Alexis Debat, who has been revealed to be the author of faked interviews.
[(ABC News, 'ORG'), (yesterday, 'DATE'), (second, 'ORDINAL'), (more than five years, 'DATE'), (Alexis Debat, 'PERSON')]
The interviews, published in a French journal, were said to have been done with prominent political figures, including former President Bill Clinton and Senator Barack Obama.
[(French, 'NORP'), (Bill Clinton, 'PERSON'), (Barack Obama, 'PERSON')]
“We going at this again with a vengeance,” said Brian Ross, the ABC correspondent who was involved in most of the reports that used information provided by Mr. Debat, whom ABC hired in November 2001.
[(Brian Ross, 'PERSON'), (ABC, 'ORG'), (Debat, 'PERSON'), (ABC, 'ORG'), (November 2001, 'DATE')]
ABC fired Mr. Debat in June after discovering that his claims of having earned a doctorate from the Sorbonne were false.
[(ABC, 'ORG'), (Debat, 'PERSON'), (June, 'DATE'), (Sorbonne, 'ORG')]
The network then investigated the reports Mr. Debat had participated in and found “they absolutely checked out,” Mr. Ross said.
[(Debat, 'PERSON'), (Ross, 'PERSON')]
Now, however, ABC is taking a further look into information Mr. Debat provided.
[(ABC, 'ORG'), (Debat, 'PERSON')]
Mr. Ross said ABC had dispatched an investigator to Pakistan to go over details of reports in which Mr. Debat provided information.
[(Ross, 'PERSON'), (ABC, 'ORG'), (Pakistan, 'GPE'), (Debat, 'PERSON')]
At the same time, The Associated Press reported last night that it also was investigating three news reports that relied on Mr. Debat for information.
[(The Associated Press, 'ORG'), (last night, 'TIME'), (three, 'CARDINAL'), (Debat, 'PERSON')]
The renewed scrutiny has been driven by revelations about Mr. Debat after a French news Web site, Rue 89, reported this week that an interview supposedly with Senator Obama was entirely made up.
[(Debat, 'PERSON'), (French, 'NORP'), (Rue 89, 'LAW'), (this week, 'DATE'), (Obama, 'PERSON')]
Mr. Debat, who could not be reached last night, sent an e-mail message to ABC yesterday saying the allegations against him “are slanderous.”
[(Debat, 'PERSON'), (last night, 'TIME'), (ABC, 'ORG'), (yesterday, 'DATE')]
He told The Washington Post Wednesday that an intermediary had spoken with Mr. Obama.
[(The Washington Post, 'ORG'), (Wednesday, 'DATE'), (Obama, 'PERSON')]
But representatives for Mr. Obama denied that he spoke with anyone connected to Mr. Debat.
[(Obama, 'PERSON'), (Debat, 'PERSON')]
Subsequently, other figures whose interviews appeared under Mr. Debat’s byline in the French magazine Politique Internationale have come forward to say they never spoke to him.
[(Debat’s, 'PERSON'), (French, 'NORP'), (Politique Internationale, 'ORG')]
These included Mr. Clinton; Mayor Michael R. Bloomberg; Alan Greenspan, the former Federal Reserve chairman; Bill Gates, the chairman of Microsoft; and House Speaker Nancy Pelosi.
[(Clinton, 'PERSON'), (Michael R. Bloomberg, 'PERSON'), (Alan Greenspan, 'PERSON'), (Federal Reserve, 'ORG'), (Bill Gates, 'PERSON'), (Microsoft, 'ORG'), (House, 'ORG'), (Nancy Pelosi, 'PERSON')]
Since his departure from ABC News in June, Mr. Debat has continued to work as a senior fellow for national security and terrorism at the Nixon Center in Washington.
[(ABC News, 'ORG'), (June, 'DATE'), (Debat, 'PERSON'), (the Nixon Center, 'FAC'), (Washington, 'GPE')]
He was quoted as a knowledgeable source in an article in The Times of London this month, saying that American military forces were planning attacks that would demolish “the entire Iranian military.” He has also been quoted by many newspapers and news services.
[(The Times of London, 'ORG'), (this month, 'DATE'), (American, 'NORP'), (Iranian, 'NORP')]
Guillemette Faure, a reporter for Rue 89, said doubts had been raised about an ABC report, with Mr. Debat as a source, during the buildup to the Iraq war.
[(Guillemette Faure, 'PERSON'), (Rue 89, 'LAW'), (ABC, 'ORG'), (Debat, 'PERSON'), (the Iraq war, 'EVENT')]
The report said that Uday Hussein, a son of Saddam Hussein, had ordered two French ballet students at gunpoint to have sex in public.
[(Uday Hussein, 'PERSON'), (Saddam Hussein, 'PERSON'), (two, 'CARDINAL'), (French, 'NORP')]
Mr. Ross said in a telephone interview yesterday that ABC News had spoken with a representative of the ballet group involved in the incident and was satisfied that it had happened and that Mr. Debat’s information about terrorist activities in Europe and Pakistan had always been supported by other sources.
[(Ross, 'PERSON'), (yesterday, 'DATE'), (ABC News, 'ORG'), (Debat’s, 'PERSON'), (Europe, 'LOC'), (Pakistan, 'GPE')]
Mr. Ross said that French officials had alerted ABC in late May that Mr. Debat’s academic credentials might not be valid and that ABC fired him promptly after verifying the information.
[(Ross, 'PERSON'), (French, 'NORP'), (ABC, 'ORG'), (late May, 'DATE'), (Debat’s, 'PERSON'), (ABC, 'ORG')]
But Pascal Riche, the editor of Rue 89, said yesterday that ABC did not hear questions about Mr. Debat’s credibility first from French officials in May.
[(Pascal Riche, 'PERSON'), (Rue 89, 'LAW'), (yesterday, 'DATE'), (ABC, 'ORG'), (Debat’s, 'PERSON'), (first, 'ORDINAL'), (French, 'NORP'), (May, 'DATE')]
He said “whistle-blowers inside ABC” had long expressed doubts about Mr. Debat.
[(Debat, 'PERSON')]
Mr. Riche said Rue 89 would have further reporting on Mr. Debat soon.
[(Riche, 'PERSON'), (Rue 89, 'LAW'), (Debat, 'PERSON')]

[]
At Connecticut Day Care Deemed "Hazardous," Backers Come to Owner's Defense
[(Connecticut Day Care Deemed "Hazardous, 'EVENT'), (Backers Come to Owner's, 'WORK_OF_ART')]
16 — Along with plastic toys and bicycles, the backyard of the day care center was littered with broken glass and a rusting Toyota Corolla resting on a jack.
[(16 —, 'QUANTITY'), (Toyota, 'ORG'), (Corolla, 'PRODUCT')]
Photographs of the inside showed water from a leaky upstairs bathtub dripping from a kitchen light fixture, an exposed electrical socket in a bedroom, phone cords dangling in the nursery and a half-opened can of pet food on an upstairs table.
[(the nursery and a half, 'DATE')]
Mounds of garbage and laundry were in plain sight.
[]
When representatives from the state’s Department of Public Health and the Department of Children and Families showed up last month at the day care center, which Collette A. Barnes was running from her house here, they discovered seven children being watched by her 14-year-old daughter in a setting they deemed “unsanitary and hazardous.” Ms. Barnes was in Florida.
[(the state’s Department of Public Health, 'ORG'), (the Department of Children and Families, 'ORG'), (last month, 'DATE'), (Collette A. Barnes, 'PERSON'), (seven, 'CARDINAL'), (14-year-old, 'DATE'), (Barnes, 'PERSON'), (Florida, 'GPE')]
Since then, the authorities have closed the center, placed Ms. Barnes’s three daughters in foster care and pursued criminal charges against Ms. Barnes, 40, that could send her to prison for more than 40 years.
[(Barnes’s, 'PERSON'), (Barnes, 'PERSON'), (40, 'DATE'), (more than 40 years, 'DATE')]
Yet customers who want to see the business reopened have leaped to her defense.
[]
“She was a great baby sitter,” said Jamie Thompson, 25.
[(Jamie Thompson, 'PERSON'), (25, 'DATE')]
Scrambling to find affordable care for her three children and her companion’s child, Ms. Thompson and he are angry, not at Ms. Barnes but at the state for shutting the center and upsetting the fragile routines that were crucial to their lives.
[(three, 'CARDINAL'), (companion’s, 'ORG'), (Thompson, 'PERSON'), (Barnes, 'PERSON')]
“If she opened now, I’d drop off my kids tomorrow morning,” Ms. Thompson said.
[(tomorrow morning,”, 'DATE'), (Thompson, 'PERSON')]
She said Ms. Barnes read to the children, helped toilet-train them and got them to try such novel meals as curry and cabbage, a Jamaican specialty.
[(Barnes, 'PERSON'), (Jamaican, 'NORP')]
Though Ms. Barnes typically charged her $170 a week per child, far less than the $400 that some places want, Ms. Thompson said she did not always earn enough as a phlebotomist to pay.
[(Barnes, 'PERSON'), (170, 'MONEY'), (400, 'MONEY'), (Thompson, 'PERSON')]
But she said that Ms. Barnes never turned her away and was accommodating when she attended night school to train for a higher-paying job. “She was like family,” Ms. Thompson said.
[(Barnes, 'PERSON'), (Thompson, 'PERSON')]
Losing the center meant she has had to forgo night school for now. “It’s put us all in a hole,” said Ms. Thompson, tears welling up as she considered sending her children to her mother in Florida as a last resort. “It’s stressful every morning trying to figure out what to do with the kids.”
[(Thompson, 'PERSON'), (Florida, 'GPE'), (kids.”, 'ORG')]
The authorities overreacted, say some neighbors and others familiar with Ms. Barnes, who bought the house at 61 Frank Street last summer. “They come down too hard on her,” said Juan Martinez, a letter carrier who once lived on the block. “It’s not like her house is worse than other people’s.”
[(Barnes, 'PERSON'), (last summer, 'DATE'), (Juan Martinez, 'PERSON'), (people’s.”, 'ORG')]
In her first public comments on the matter, Ms. Barnes tried to maintain a sunny demeanor this month in her mother’s living room.
[(Barnes, 'PERSON'), (this month, 'DATE')]
A picture of her as a young woman who had just earned an associate’s degree in business hung on the wall.
[]
“Miss Trouble, right?” said Ms. Barnes, showing exasperation with the news accounts and editorials that have taken her to task.
[(Barnes, 'PERSON')]
The house that Ms. Barnes bought on heavy credit last year for $433,000 and nearly lost to foreclosure this summer was supposed to have been her ticket out of poverty.
[(Barnes, 'PERSON'), (last year, 'DATE'), (433,000, 'MONEY'), (this summer, 'DATE')]
Thinking she might turn occasional baby-sitting jobs into a business, she said, “I looked at many houses, and that was one I clung to.”
[(“I, 'PERSON')]
She said she was smitten by the ample backyard.
[]
By December, she had applied for a state license to run a day care center out of the house.
[(December, 'DATE')]
Inspectors from the Department of Public Health required her to fix deficiencies including a missing railing and debris in the driveway.
[(the Department of Public Health, 'ORG')]
The license arrived in February.
[(February, 'DATE')]
On a street that has some public housing, as well as splashes of sunflowers and an occasional backyard trampoline, neighbors welcomed Ms. Barnes’s improvements to the property.
[(Barnes’s, 'PERSON')]
“She was fixing it up, little by little,” said a neighbor who declined to identify herself.
[(little,”, 'ORG')]
Still, one customer complained to the state about lead paint at the house, prompting another inspection and another round of repairs.
[(one, 'CARDINAL')]
Ms. Thompson said she thought the same parent also summoned the authorities on Aug. 30, which led to the closing.
[(Thompson, 'PERSON'), (Aug. 30, 'DATE')]
Although Ms. Barnes would not identify who she believed notified the authorities, she said, “This is an inside job.”
[(Barnes, 'PERSON')]
In June, the mortgage holder began foreclosure proceedings when Ms. Barnes fell behind on her payments.
[(June, 'DATE'), (Barnes, 'PERSON')]
But by early last month she had come up with the $9,000 she owed, out of proceeds from a state-run program called Care for Kids, which subsidizes day care services for the indigent.
[(early last month, 'DATE'), (9,000, 'MONEY'), (Care for Kids, 'ORG')]
Eager to show off the house to friends and family and to celebrate her 40th birthday on Sept.
[(40th, 'ORDINAL'), (Sept., 'DATE')]
7, Ms. Barnes said she boarded a train for Florida on Aug. 27 to fetch her 69-year-old father. “It was not a vacation,” she said.
[(Barnes, 'PERSON'), (Florida, 'GPE'), (Aug. 27, 'DATE'), (69-year-old, 'DATE'), (“It, 'ORG'), (vacation,”, 'NORP')]
She said that she had asked an adult, whom she refused to identify, to fill in at the day care center, and that she never intended for her 14-year-old daughter, Channeisha Crosbie, to be in charge.
[(14-year-old, 'DATE'), (Channeisha Crosbie, 'PERSON')]
Ms. Thompson said she knew “weeks in advance” that Ms. Barnes had planned to take time off and assumed that a responsible adult would mind the children. “I trusted her,” she said. “I still trust her.”
[(Thompson, 'PERSON'), (Barnes, 'PERSON'), (“I, 'PERSON'), (“I, 'PERSON'), (her.”, 'ORG')]
Ms. Barnes said that on her arrival in Florida on Aug. 29, she learned that her replacement had lasted only one day.
[(Barnes, 'PERSON'), (Florida, 'GPE'), (Aug. 29, 'DATE')]
Feeling there was little she could do, she hoped that her 64-year-old mother, Carmen Barnes, as well as her daughters Channeisha and Charlesha Crosbie, 17, could oversee the center until her return.
[(64-year-old, 'DATE'), (Carmen Barnes, 'PERSON'), (Charlesha Crosbie, 'PERSON'), (17, 'DATE')]
When representatives from the state’s Department of Public Health and Department of Children and Families showed up and demanded to be let in, the police said, Ms. Barnes’s mother was not there.
[(the state’s Department of Public Health and Department of Children and Families, 'ORG'), (Barnes’s, 'PERSON')]
Ms. Barnes’s 14-year-old daughter refused to open the door — something Connecticut considers grounds for revoking a license.
[(Barnes’s, 'PERSON'), (14-year-old, 'DATE'), (Connecticut, 'GPE')]
Ms. Barnes said her daughter was simply wary of the strangers and was trained not to let anyone in. “They were peeping in the back,” she said.
[(Barnes, 'PERSON')]
When Channeisha finally opened the door, the authorities found her watching her 9-year-old sister, Channelle, and six other children ranging in age from 3 months to 7 years.
[(Channeisha, 'GPE'), (9-year-old, 'DATE'), (Channelle, 'ORG'), (six, 'CARDINAL'), (age from 3 months to 7 years, 'DATE')]
Arriving soon after, Ms. Barnes’s mother told the authorities she had left briefly to get an inhaler from her house a few blocks away because she was wheezing.
[(Barnes’s, 'PERSON')]
She conceded that she first tried to cover up her daughter’s whereabouts.
[(daughter’s, 'NORP')]
“Yes, I did lie to them,” Carmen Barnes said. “I said she went to the doctor, because I did not want to create a situation.”
[(them,” Carmen Barnes, 'ORG'), (“I, 'PERSON')]
She and her daughter insisted that the worst of the plumbing and electrical problems arose after Ms. Barnes left for Florida.
[(Barnes, 'PERSON'), (Florida, 'GPE')]
William Gerrish, a spokesman for the state’s health department, said he could only assume that “the facility declined significantly” since the earlier inspections.
[(William Gerrish, 'PERSON'), (the state’s health department, 'ORG')]
“We view it very seriously,” said Lt. Sean Cooney, a spokesman for the Stamford police. “This could have ended in tragedy.”
[(Sean Cooney, 'PERSON'), (Stamford, 'GPE')]
Photographs taken by the authorities on Aug. 30 show the wet kitchen light fixture, the exposed bedroom socket, the dangling phone cords and a sink stacked with dishes.
[(Aug. 30, 'DATE')]
The elder Ms. Barnes disputed that the interior was as squalid as the police and health officials claimed. “Everybody has a basket in their house with clothes and a pot on their stove,” she said.
[(Barnes, 'PERSON'), (stove,”, 'PRODUCT')]
And she insisted that the dishes that the police asserted were dirty were freshly washed and left in the sink to dry.
[]
Local health officials proclaimed the house “unfit for human habitation” and forbade its reoccupation without permission.
[]
A notice posted on the door cited peeling paint, exposed electrical wiring, dangerous leaks and an “inordinate amount of garbage and clothing” as conditions posing danger to the “health and safety of the occupants and people living in the vicinity.”
[]
State health officials who suspended Ms. Barnes’s license also cited her “failure to show good judgment” as well as her failure to have enrollment and medical records for all the children there available for inspection.
[(Barnes’s, 'PERSON')]
Public health officials will give Ms. Barnes — who denied all the charges — a chance to contest the suspension of her license.
[(Barnes —, 'PERSON')]
But most problematic for her are the criminal charges she faces when she appears in court today.
[(today, 'DATE')]
Learning from news accounts that the authorities wanted to arrest her, she surrendered to the police at dawn on Sept.
[(dawn, 'TIME'), (Sept., 'DATE')]
4 to avoid being led away in handcuffs, and since then has been free on $5,000 bond.
[(4, 'CARDINAL'), (5,000, 'MONEY')]
She was charged with eight counts of risk of injury to a minor and eight counts of reckless endangerment in the second degree.
[(eight, 'CARDINAL'), (eight, 'CARDINAL'), (second, 'ORDINAL')]
The sheer number of counts — one applied on each charge for each child enrolled that day and for her own two under-age children — means she could spend the next 48 years of her life in prison.
[(— one, 'PERSON'), (two, 'CARDINAL'), (the next 48 years, 'DATE')]
Alain Delaquérière contributed reporting.
[(Alain Delaquérière, 'PERSON')]

[]
Jets Hope It Starts To Add Up On Defense
[(Jets Hope, 'PERSON')]
If the Jets" defense has been playing dirty tricks, as was alleged by Ravens Coach Brian Billick, statistics have not reflected an advantage.
[(Jets, 'PERSON'), (Ravens Coach, 'PERSON'), (Brian Billick, 'PERSON')]
The Jets have not recorded a sack or an interception in their first two games, and that is the first time that has happened since 1976, according to the team's Web site.
[(Jets, 'PERSON'), (first, 'ORDINAL'), (two, 'CARDINAL'), (first, 'ORDINAL'), (1976, 'DATE')]
Last season, they had 35 sacks and 16 interceptions.
[(Last season, 'DATE'), (35, 'CARDINAL'), (16, 'CARDINAL')]
Free safety Kerry Rhodes, who had four interceptions last season, said he was considering offering some sort of cash bonus for the player who produced the first turnover.
[(Kerry Rhodes, 'PERSON'), (four, 'CARDINAL'), (last season, 'DATE'), (first, 'ORDINAL')]
"They're going to see a very determined safety," Rhodes said, referring to the Miami Dolphins, whom the Jets play at Giants Stadium tomorrow.
[(Jets, 'PERSON'), (Giants Stadium, 'FAC'), (tomorrow, 'DATE')]
As for sacks, defensive end David Bowens is one member of the Jets who is hungry for one or more.
[(David Bowens, 'PERSON'), (one, 'CARDINAL'), (Jets, 'PERSON')]
"My experience in nine years is that sacks do come in bunches," said Bowens, who played for the Dolphins the past two seasons.
[(nine years, 'DATE'), (Bowens, 'PERSON'), (Dolphins, 'PERSON'), (the past two seasons, 'DATE')]
Last year, I went seven games without getting one and then I got one in each of the last six games.
[(Last year, 'DATE'), (seven, 'CARDINAL'), (each of the last, 'DATE'), (six, 'CARDINAL')]
Interceptions and sacks have the power to demoralize a quarterback and change the momentum of a game.
[]
How tempting it would be for a defense to resort to trickery - perhaps calling out signals to disrupt an offense.
[]
That was the accusation Billick leveled at the Jets on Monday, a day after his team beat them, 20-13.
[(Billick, 'PERSON'), (Jets, 'PERSON'), (Monday, 'DATE'), (a day, 'DATE'), (20, 'CARDINAL')]
The Jets denied those claims.
[(Jets, 'PERSON')]
"I know that I don't have time for it," linebacker Jonathan Vilma said.
[(Jonathan Vilma, 'PERSON')]
I know that I have way too much on my plate to think about without trying to make a dummy call.
[]
The Jets have come up with zero in another defensive category.; they have not forced a single fumble.
[(zero, 'CARDINAL')]
Coach Eric Mangini said his staff tracks forced fumbles, interceptions and batted balls on a board during practice.
[(Eric Mangini, 'PERSON')]
He also said the team analyzed film of opponents in these categories, looking for weaknesses that could lead to turnovers.
[]
"Maybe they don't protect the back of the football, they don't protect the tip of the football, they carry it away from their body," he said.
[]
RUNNING FOR THE MONEY Thomas Jones and Leon Washington of the Jets are among the 15 N.F.L. running backs who will be donating a dollar for every rushing yard they gain this season to the Rush for Walter program, with the proceeds going primarily to the N.F.L. Retired Players Medical and Assistance Fund.
[(Thomas Jones, 'PERSON'), (Leon Washington, 'PERSON'), (Jets, 'PERSON'), (15, 'CARDINAL'), (N.F.L., 'ORG'), (this season, 'DATE'), (Walter, 'PERSON'), (the N.F.L. Retired Players Medical and Assistance Fund, 'ORG')]
The program was started by Saints running back Reggie Bush in alliance with Walter Payton's widow, Connie, who oversees the Walter and Connie Payton Foundation.
[(Reggie Bush, 'PERSON'), (Walter Payton's, 'PERSON'), (Connie, 'ORG'), (the Walter and Connie Payton Foundation, 'ORG')]
Connie Payton, who grew up in New Orleans, will return to her hometown on Monday to watch Bush and the Saints play host to the Tennessee Titans.
[(Connie Payton, 'PERSON'), (New Orleans, 'GPE'), (Monday, 'DATE'), (Bush, 'PERSON'), (Saints, 'ORG'), (Tennessee, 'GPE')]
Jones said he received a personal letter from Bush, a second-year player, asking him to be a part of the program, and he could not resist.
[(Jones, 'PERSON'), (Bush, 'PERSON'), (second-year, 'DATE')]
"Walter Payton was somebody I definitely looked up to as a kid," he said.
[(Walter Payton, 'PERSON')]
DOLPHINS" THOMAS WON'T PLAY Zach Thomas, the Miami Dolphins" middle linebacker, will be held out of tomorrow's game against the Jets because of concussion-related symptoms.
[(Zach Thomas, 'PERSON'), (tomorrow, 'DATE'), (Jets, 'PERSON')]
EVERETT GOES TO TEXAS Bills tight end Kevin Everett returned to his native Texas to be closer to his family for the next phase of his recovery from a spinal-cord injury.
[(TEXAS, 'GPE'), (Kevin Everett, 'PERSON'), (Texas, 'GPE')]
Accompanied by his mother, Everett was transferred from Buffalo to a hospital in Houston that provides medical rehabilitation for patients of catastrophic trauma.
[(Everett, 'PERSON'), (Buffalo, 'GPE'), (Houston, 'GPE')]
Doctors initially feared that Everett would not walk again, but they now say he could walk within weeks.
[(Everett, 'PERSON'), (weeks, 'DATE')]
A DEBATE IN SEATTLE Shaun Alexander, the Seahawks running back, will continue to wear a cast over his sprained left wrist, but Coach Mike Holmgren is trying to get him to change the device's look for tomorrow's game against the Bengals.
[(Seahawks, 'PERSON'), (Mike Holmgren, 'PERSON'), (tomorrow, 'DATE'), (Bengals, 'ORG')]
Holmgren said with a laugh: "I'm arguing about the color.
[(Holmgren, 'PERSON')]
I'd like him to have it black.
[]
He wants it white.
[]
So we're still debating that.
[]
I think it looks cooler.
[]
You have to look cool out there.
[]

[]
Warner Is Hospitalized - New York Times
[(Warner, 'ORG'), (Hospitalized - New York Times, 'ORG')]
Senator John W. Warner, Republican of Virginia, was treated at a hospital to correct an abnormal heart rhythm, atrial fibrillation, his office said.
[(John W. Warner, 'PERSON'), (Republican, 'NORP'), (Virginia, 'GPE')]
The statement said a second routine procedure would be performed today at Inova Fairfax Hospital.
[(second, 'ORDINAL'), (today, 'DATE'), (Inova Fairfax Hospital, 'ORG')]
The statement said doctors “fully anticipate” that Mr. Warner, 80, would be home by the weekend and back at work next week.
[(Warner, 'PERSON'), (80, 'DATE'), (the weekend, 'DATE'), (next week, 'DATE')]
Mr. Warner, a five-term senator and one of Congress’s most influential voices on the war in Iraq, announced Aug. 31 that he would not seek re-election.
[(Warner, 'PERSON'), (five, 'CARDINAL'), (one, 'CARDINAL'), (Congress’s, 'ORG'), (Iraq, 'GPE'), (Aug. 31, 'DATE')]

[]
2 Detectives Hurt in Bronx Shooting
[(2, 'CARDINAL'), (Bronx Shooting, 'GPE')]
Two New York City police detectives were wounded this morning in a gun battle in a Bronx alley while trying to arrest a man suspected of shooting two people in a bodega in July, the police said.
[(Two, 'CARDINAL'), (New York City, 'GPE'), (this morning, 'TIME'), (Bronx, 'GPE'), (two, 'CARDINAL'), (July, 'DATE')]
Both detectives were grazed by bullets, the police said, and were in stable condition at St. Barnabas Hospital.
[(St. Barnabas Hospital, 'FAC')]
At a news conference this morning at the hospital, Mayor Michael R. Bloomberg repeated his call to “get guns out of the hands of criminals and off the streets.”
[(this morning, 'TIME'), (Michael R. Bloomberg, 'PERSON')]
“I am always impressed by the courage and the sense of duty I get when I visit wounded N.Y.P.D. officers in the hospital,” the mayor said. “This could have been much worse.”
[(“I, 'PERSON')]
The shootout occurred about 5:30 a.m.
[(about 5:30 a.m., 'TIME')]
Eastern time, after five officers from the Bronx Warrants Violent Felony Squad moved to arrest the suspect, Jermaine Taylor, 20, in a second-floor apartment at 2422 Webster Avenue in the Tremont section, the police said.
[(five, 'CARDINAL'), (the Bronx Warrants Violent Felony Squad, 'ORG'), (Jermaine Taylor, 'PERSON'), (20, 'DATE'), (second, 'ORDINAL'), (2422, 'DATE'), (Webster Avenue, 'WORK_OF_ART'), (Tremont, 'GPE')]
As some officers went to the apartment door, others circled around to an alley behind the building, where they heard someone yank out a window air-conditioner.
[]
Moments later, the detectives saw Mr. Taylor scramble out the window, leap down to the alley and open fire on them with a 9-millimeter semiautomatic pistol, the police said.
[(Taylor, 'PERSON'), (9, 'CARDINAL')]
He fired six shots, grazing Detective William Gonzalez, 42, in the right shin, and Detective Daniel Rivera, 41, in the forehead, the police said.
[(six, 'CARDINAL'), (William Gonzalez, 'PERSON'), (42, 'DATE'), (Detective Daniel Rivera, 'ORG'), (41, 'DATE')]
Both of the wounded detectives and Detective Thomas Murphy, 39, returned fire, unleashing 13 shots at Mr. Taylor, the police said.
[(Detective, 'ORG'), (Thomas Murphy, 'PERSON'), (39, 'DATE'), (13, 'CARDINAL'), (Taylor, 'PERSON')]
Mr. Taylor, who was not hit, was arrested by the officers.
[(Taylor, 'PERSON')]
Inside the apartment, the police said they found seven people and three pit bulls.
[(seven, 'CARDINAL'), (three, 'CARDINAL')]
The people, who had not been charged with any crime this morning, were being questioned, and the dogs were removed by emergency service officers, the police said.
[]
Mr. Taylor, who fractured his pelvis leaping from the window, is a suspect in a July 2 shooting in front of a bodega at 320 Holland Avenue, the police said; one person was shot in the leg and a second shot in the torso in that incident.
[(Taylor, 'PERSON'), (July 2, 'DATE'), (320, 'CARDINAL'), (Holland Avenue, 'FAC'), (one, 'CARDINAL'), (second, 'ORDINAL')]
Police Commissioner Raymond W. Kelly said there were three rounds remaining in the 9-millimeter pistol when it was recovered from Mr. Taylor.
[(Raymond W. Kelly, 'PERSON'), (three, 'CARDINAL'), (9, 'CARDINAL'), (Taylor, 'PERSON')]
“The mayor and I are often asked how the N.Y.P.D. manages to continue to drive crime down while the rest of the nation experiences increases,” the commissioner said at the news conference. “The reasons are here in this hospital this morning.”
[(N.Y.P.D., 'GPE')]
Mathew R. Warren contributed reporting.
[(Mathew R. Warren, 'PERSON')]

[]
Midday New York Numbers — 468; Lucky Sum — 18
[(New York Numbers, 'ORG'), (468, 'CARDINAL'), (18, 'CARDINAL')]
Midday New York Win 4 — 4817; Lucky Sum — 20
[(Midday, 'GPE'), (New York Win, 'ORG'), (20, 'CARDINAL')]
New York Numbers — 050; Lucky Sum — 5
[(New York Numbers, 'ORG'), (050, 'CARDINAL'), (5, 'CARDINAL')]
New York Win 4 — 2587; Lucky Sum — 22
[(New York Win 4 — 2587, 'ORG'), (22, 'CARDINAL')]
New York Take 5 — 4, 6, 18, 29, 30
[(New York, 'GPE'), (5 —, 'QUANTITY'), (4, 'CARDINAL'), (6, 'DATE'), (18, 'DATE'), (29, 'DATE'), (30, 'CARDINAL')]
Midday New Jersey Pick 3 — 748
[(Midday, 'GPE'), (New Jersey, 'GPE'), (748, 'CARDINAL')]
Midday New Jersey Pick 4 — 6533
[(Midday, 'GPE'), (New Jersey, 'GPE')]
New Jersey Pick 3 — 243
[(New Jersey, 'GPE'), (243, 'CARDINAL')]
New Jersey Pick 4 — 2844
[(New Jersey, 'GPE')]
New Jersey Cash 5 — 4, 6, 14, 26, 29
[(New Jersey, 'GPE'), (5 —, 'QUANTITY'), (4, 'CARDINAL'), (6, 'DATE'), (14, 'DATE'), (26, 'DATE'), (29, 'CARDINAL')]
New Jersey Pick-6 Lotto — 2, 8, 15, 21, 39, 44
[(New Jersey, 'GPE'), (2, 'CARDINAL'), (8, 'DATE'), (15, 'DATE'), (21, 'DATE'), (39, 'DATE'), (44, 'DATE')]
Connecticut Midday 3 — 135
[(Connecticut, 'GPE'), (3, 'CARDINAL'), (135, 'CARDINAL')]
Connecticut Midday 4 — 3232
[(Connecticut, 'GPE'), (4 —, 'QUANTITY')]
Connecticut Daily — 914
[(Connecticut Daily, 'ORG'), (914, 'CARDINAL')]
Connecticut Play 4 — 9685
[(Connecticut, 'GPE'), (4 —, 'QUANTITY')]
Connecticut Cash 5 — 1, 9, 10, 16, 18 Oct. 3, 2007
[(Connecticut, 'GPE'), (5 — 1, 'QUANTITY'), (9, 'DATE'), (10, 'DATE'), (16, 'DATE'), (18 Oct. 3, 2007, 'DATE')]
New York Lotto — 21, 26, 36, 39, 51, 54; supplementary, 49

[]
The New Advertising Outlet: Your Life
[(The New Advertising Outlet: Your Life, 'ORG')]
STEVE SAENZ used to run a 10K race in 36 minutes.
[(10, 'CARDINAL'), (36 minutes, 'TIME')]
But last spring — 20 years, 2 children and 50 pounds later — he found himself seriously out of shape.
[(last spring, 'DATE'), (20 years, 'DATE'), (2, 'CARDINAL'), (50 pounds, 'QUANTITY')]
A new Web site from Nike, he says, has brought him back on track.
[(Nike, 'ORG')]
Since April, Mr. Saenz, 53, has been running with a Nike+, a small sensor in his running shoes that tracks his progress on an Apple iPod he carries.
[(April, 'DATE'), (Saenz, 'PERSON'), (53, 'DATE'), (Nike+, 'ORG'), (Apple, 'ORG')]
After each run near his home in Louisville, Ky., he docks the iPod into his computer and posts details of his run on the Nike+ Web site.
[(Louisville, 'GPE'), (Ky., 'GPE'), (iPod, 'ORG'), (Nike+, 'ORG')]
There, he has made friends with other runners around the world who post running routes, meet up in the real world and encourage one another on the site.
[]
Nike’s famous swoosh is there all along.
[]
For Nike, this is advertising.
[(Nike, 'ORG')]
“It’s a very different way to connect with consumers,” says Trevor Edwards, Nike’s corporate vice president for global brand and category management. “People are coming into it on average three times a week.
[(Trevor Edwards, 'PERSON'), (three, 'CARDINAL')]
So we’re not having to go to them.”
[]
The success of Nike+ is bad news for the traditional media companies that have long made money from Nike’s television commercials and glossy magazine ads.
[(Nike+, 'ORG')]
Last year, Nike spent just 33 percent of its $678 million United States advertising budget on ads with television networks and other traditional media companies.
[(Last year, 'DATE'), (Nike, 'ORG'), (just 33 percent, 'PERCENT'), ($678 million, 'MONEY'), (United States, 'GPE')]
That’s down from 55 percent 10 years ago, according to the trade publication Advertising Age.
[(55 percent, 'PERCENT'), (10 years ago, 'DATE'), (Advertising Age, 'ORG')]
“We’re not in the business of keeping the media companies alive,” Mr. Edwards says he tells many media executives. “We’re in the business of connecting with consumers.”
[(Edwards, 'PERSON')]
Mr. Edwards may be more blunt than most.
[(Edwards, 'PERSON')]
But many large marketers are taking huge chunks of money out of their budgets for traditional media and using the funds to develop new, more direct interactions with consumers — not only on the Internet, but also through in-person events.
[]
Adventurous companies like Nike have been experimenting with these alternatives since the 1990s.
[(Nike, 'ORG'), (the 1990s, 'DATE')]
But now, even the most conventional marketers are making these alternatives a permanent — and ever bigger — part of their advertising budgets.
[]
Last year, Johnson & Johnson decided to boycott the so-called upfronts, an annual event when advertisers get together with television executives to negotiate for commercial time.
[(Last year, 'DATE'), (Johnson & Johnson, 'ORG')]
In August, General Motors said that 2008 would be the last year for its longtime sponsorship of the Olympics.
[(August, 'DATE'), (General Motors, 'ORG'), (2008, 'DATE'), (the last year, 'DATE'), (Olympics, 'EVENT')]
In May, A. G. Lafley, the chief executive of Procter & Gamble, told financial analysts that the company would spend less on traditional media and more on its Web site, in-store advertising and promotional events.
[(May, 'DATE'), (A. G. Lafley, 'PERSON'), (Procter & Gamble, 'ORG')]
“If you step back and look at our mix across most of the major brands,” Mr. Lafley said, “it is clearly shifting.”
[(Lafley, 'PERSON'), (“it, 'PERSON')]
Add it up, and the money flowing out of the traditional media is huge — even at a time when ad budgets in general are growing, advertising research shows.
[]
The 25 companies that spent the most on advertising over the last five years cut their spending last year in traditional media by about $767 million, according to Advertising Age and TNS Media Intelligence.
[(25, 'CARDINAL'), (the last five years, 'DATE'), (last year, 'DATE'), (about $767 million, 'MONEY'), (Advertising Age, 'ORG')]
And in the first half of this year, those companies decreased their media spending an additional 3 percent, or $446 million, to $14.53 billion, according to TNS Media Intelligence.
[(the first half of this year, 'DATE'), (an additional 3 percent, 'PERCENT'), ($446 million, 'MONEY'), ($14.53 billion, 'MONEY'), (TNS Media Intelligence, 'ORG')]
True, Nike increased its spending on traditional media in the United States by 3 percent from 2003 to 2006, to $220.5 million.
[(Nike, 'ORG'), (the United States, 'GPE'), (3 percent, 'PERCENT'), (2003, 'DATE'), (2006, 'DATE'), ($220.5 million, 'MONEY')]
But in the same period, it increased its nonmedia ad spending 33 percent, to $457.9 million, according to the Advertising Age data.
[(33 percent, 'PERCENT'), ($457.9 million, 'MONEY')]
Behind the shift is a fundamental change in Nike’s view of the role of advertising.
[]
No longer are ads primarily meant to grab a person’s attention while they’re trying to do something else — like reading an article.
[]
Nike executives say that much of the company’s future advertising spending will take the form of services for consumers, like workout advice, online communities and local sports competitions.
[(Nike, 'ORG')]
“We want to find a way to enhance the experience and services, rather than looking for a way to interrupt people from getting to where they want to go,” said Stefan Olander, global director for brand connections at Nike. “How can we provide a service that the consumer goes, ‘Wow, you really made this easier for me’?”
[(Stefan Olander, 'PERSON'), (Nike, 'ORG'), (‘Wow, 'PERSON')]
BUT media companies rely on advertising to pay the bulk of their programming and newsroom costs.
[]
Traditionally, the “service” provided by advertising was cheaper media content for consumers.
[]
But the services of the future may be virtual workout coaches, map applications for cellphones, health advice and matchmaking services.
[]
Nike executives portray the shift in strategy as a return to the company’s roots in the 1970s, when, in the words of an early magazine ad, Nike grew through “word-of-foot marketing.” In the early days, Nike displayed posters from local races in stores and was host for local runs on the West Coast.
[(Nike, 'ORG'), (the 1970s, 'DATE'), (Nike, 'ORG'), (the early days, 'DATE'), (Nike, 'ORG'), (the West Coast, 'LOC')]
Most early employees at Nike were runners themselves, often disciples of Bill Bowerman, the former college track coach, who founded Nike with Phil Knight, the company’s current chairman.
[(Nike, 'ORG'), (Bill Bowerman, 'PERSON'), (Nike, 'ORG'), (Phil Knight, 'PERSON')]
In the 1980s, Nike began the large television campaigns that propelled the brand to global fame.
[(the 1980s, 'DATE'), (Nike, 'ORG'), (fame, 'ORG')]
Early ones included ads starring Michael Jordan and Spike Lee.
[(Michael Jordan, 'PERSON'), (Spike Lee, 'PERSON')]
Its “Revolution” ad in 1987 featured the Beatles song of the same name to introduce the Air Max shoe.
[(1987, 'DATE'), (Beatles, 'PERSON'), (Air Max, 'ORG')]
And the “Just Do It” series in 1988 showcased images of athletes, including a wheelchair racer and a runner who was 80.
[(1988, 'DATE'), (80, 'DATE')]
In the 1990s, Nike ran ads with Tiger Woods and the United States women’s soccer team that inspired fans and became part of sports culture.
[(the 1990s, 'DATE'), (Nike, 'ORG'), (Tiger Woods, 'PERSON'), (the United States, 'GPE')]
Nike continues to have a strong and ubiquitous presence on television by sponsoring famous athletes.
[(Nike, 'ORG')]
And almost 70 percent of the company’s traditional ad spending was for TV commercials in 2006, though that share dropped to 45 percent for the first half of this year, according to Nielsen Monitor-Plus.
Today, however, many Nike ads are shown only on the Internet.
[(Today, 'DATE'), (Nike, 'ORG')]
Wayne Rooney, the British soccer player, is currently featured in a series of online videos for Nike.
[(Wayne Rooney, 'PERSON'), (British, 'NORP'), (Nike, 'ORG')]
In 2005, Nike placed a 2-minute, 46-second clip of the Brazilian soccer player Ronaldinho online, instead of on TV.
[(2005, 'DATE'), (Nike, 'ORG'), (2-minute, 'TIME'), (46-second, 'TIME'), (Brazilian, 'NORP'), (Ronaldinho, 'PRODUCT')]
The video has had more than 17 million views on YouTube and became so well known that some television networks like Sky Sports and the BBC showed it in their news coverage — free.
[(more than 17 million, 'CARDINAL'), (YouTube, 'ORG'), (Sky Sports, 'ORG'), (BBC, 'ORG')]
“We don’t automatically think about television anymore,” said Joaquin Hidalgo, vice president for global brand marketing at Nike. “There was a time when brands like Nike could tell kids through the medium of television what was cool, what was in, what was not in, because that was the only window they had into the world.
[(anymore,”, 'ORG'), (Joaquin Hidalgo, 'PERSON'), (Nike, 'ORG'), (Nike, 'ORG')]
That has completely changed now.”
[(now.”, 'PERSON')]
More confirmation that television ads were losing influence came in 2005, when a series of commercials for the Nike ID shoe flopped.
[(2005, 'DATE'), (Nike ID, 'ORG')]
The 10 ads for the Nike ID, a design-it-yourself shoe, ran that April on MTV — just the place a marketer might consider ideal for such a message.
[(10, 'CARDINAL'), (Nike, 'ORG'), (April, 'DATE'), (MTV, 'ORG')]
Now, Mr. Edwards laughs about that campaign.
[(Edwards, 'PERSON')]
“I could question whether the work was too creative or just ineffective, but it didn’t work in terms of conversion,” he said in an interview at Nike’s headquarters in Beaverton, Ore. “We didn’t see sales go up.
[(“I, 'PERSON'), (conversion,”, 'ORG'), (Nike’s, 'NORP'), (Beaverton, 'GPE'), (Ore., 'GPE')]
It was just nothing.
[]
It was like we ran them, and waited and nothing happened.”
[(happened.”, 'PERSON')]
SOMEWHERE along the path toward big-box stores and blockbuster brands, mass advertising lost a good part of its impact.
[]
Consumers began splitting their time on the couch between more and more diversions — video games, instant messaging and hundreds of TV channels.
[(hundreds, 'CARDINAL')]
Content exploded on the Internet, with free articles and videos available whenever consumers wanted them.
[(Content, 'ORG')]
And for some people with digital video recorders, the idea of watching a television commercial has started to seem quaint.
[]
“We are all concerned about when DVR penetration has reached critical mass and consumers have been trained to skip all advertising,” said Lee Doyle, chief executive for North America at Mediaedge:cia, an agency that buys ad space. “That’s the world we’re all afraid of.”
[(DVR, 'ORG'), (Lee Doyle, 'PERSON'), (North America, 'LOC'), (cia, 'ORG')]
A glance at ad revenue at several big companies from last year shows the trend.
[(last year, 'DATE')]
At the Tribune Company and The New York Times Company, ad revenue increased less than 1 percent last year.
[(the Tribune Company and The New York Times Company, 'ORG'), (less than 1 percent, 'PERCENT'), (last year, 'DATE')]
Time Inc., the magazine unit of Time Warner, reported ad revenue increases of only 2 percent last year.
[(Time Inc., 'ORG'), (Time Warner, 'ORG'), (only 2 percent, 'PERCENT'), (last year, 'DATE')]
GemStar TV Guide was down 9 percent.
[(GemStar TV Guide, 'ORG'), (9 percent, 'PERCENT')]
In radio, ad revenue at Westwood One fell 11 percent.
[(One, 'CARDINAL'), (11 percent, 'PERCENT')]
Of course, consumer brands have never spent every cent of their advertising budgets on television commercials, radio spots and print ads.
[(every cent, 'MONEY')]
For many years, companies have also mailed promotions to people’s homes, sponsored sports and community events and paid for signs within stores.
[(many years, 'DATE')]
But there is a growing interest in these and other, newer alternatives to commercials and newspaper pages.
[]
Kraft is paying to advertise in a virtual supermarket in the online world called Second Life.
[(Kraft, 'ORG'), (Second Life, 'ORG')]
Continental Airlines advertises on chopstick packets, Geico on turnstiles, McDonald’s on the floor of sports arenas and Walt Disney on the paper used on examination tables in doctors’ offices.
[(Continental Airlines, 'ORG'), (Geico, 'ORG'), (Walt Disney, 'LOC'), (doctors’, 'DATE')]
Well-known brands are also trying new approaches, hoping to generate buzz both online and off.
[]
Procter & Gamble, for example, opened a temporary Charmin-brand public bathroom in Manhattan.
[(Procter & Gamble, 'ORG'), (Manhattan, 'GPE')]
Microsoft dropped thousands of parachutes holding software onto a town in Illinois last year, and Target suspended the magician David Blaine in a gyroscope above Times Square for two days.
[(Microsoft, 'ORG'), (thousands, 'CARDINAL'), (Illinois, 'GPE'), (last year, 'DATE'), (Target, 'PERSON'), (David Blaine, 'PERSON'), (Times Square, 'FAC'), (two days, 'DATE')]
Some advertisers make their own content and post it online, sidestepping the media outlets.
[]
Burger King has created video games, and Sprite, which is owned by Coca-Cola, is running a social networking site for cellphone users.
[(Burger King, 'ORG'), (Sprite, 'PRODUCT'), (Coca-Cola, 'ORG')]
Digital media spending is doubling every year at many big companies, industry data indicate.
[(Digital, 'ORG')]
But the research firm Outsell found this year that 58 percent of marketers’ online spending went to their own Web sites, rather than to paid ads.
[(Outsell, 'ORG'), (this year, 'DATE'), (58 percent, 'PERCENT'), (marketers’, 'GPE')]
More than two million people visited Nike-owned Web sites in July, according to Nielsen//NetRatings.
[(More than two million, 'CARDINAL'), (Nike, 'ORG'), (July, 'DATE')]
Nike’s global sales have climbed in the last four years — to more than $16 billion from $10 billion.
[(the last four years, 'DATE'), (more than $16 billion, 'MONEY'), ($10 billion, 'MONEY')]
And executives say the new type of marketing is a part of that trend.
[]
The company plans to use the Nike+ idea in other sports categories, which could include basketball, tennis and soccer.
[(Nike+, 'ORG')]
While $29 for a Nike+ sensor hardly covers the cost of the device and the site maintenance and customer service, Mr. Edwards coolly points out that Nike+ is as much about marketing as it is about product.
[(29, 'MONEY'), (Nike+, 'ORG'), (Edwards, 'PERSON'), (Nike+, 'ORG')]
AS consumers spend more time online, running their virtual lives and connecting with other people more through typing than talking, Nike executives contend that they also want more physical interaction with brands.
[(Nike, 'ORG')]
Nike is running more events on the ground, like last year’s three-on-three soccer matches for youths in 37 countries and its San Francisco marathon for women.
[(Nike, 'ORG'), (three, 'CARDINAL'), (37, 'CARDINAL'), (San Francisco, 'GPE')]
Nike even calls the third floor of its New York store the “Nike Running Club.” There, runners can map out running routes, receive training advice and attend an evening speaker series — all free, even if they trot in wearing Adidas or Brooks sneakers.
[(Nike, 'ORG'), (third, 'ORDINAL'), (New York, 'GPE'), (Brooks, 'ORG')]
The company pays 5 coaches and 17 pacers to lead runs three times a week in Central Park.
[(5, 'CARDINAL'), (17, 'CARDINAL'), (three, 'CARDINAL'), (Central Park, 'LOC')]
Nike running-gear sales clerks are expected to join in.
[(Nike, 'ORG')]
The goal is to use the club to endear people to the brand and to provide opportunities for them to try products.
[]
At a recent Tuesday night gathering, Linda Martello, 34, an executive assistant, said she was grateful to Nike.
[(a recent Tuesday night, 'TIME'), (Linda Martello, 'PERSON'), (34, 'DATE'), (Nike, 'ORG')]
After she injured one of her calf muscles, she said, a Nike coach helped her figure out that she was wearing the wrong shoes.
[(Nike, 'ORG')]
She, of course, bought a pair of Nikes.
[(Nikes, 'ORG')]
“I love it here, I do,” she said as she stretched for the evening run.
[(“I, 'PERSON'), (evening, 'TIME')]
Ms. Martello stood to head out on the run.
[(Martello, 'PERSON')]
“And they’re not pushing product in my face, as if I was shopping,” she continues. “That’s why I come here.
[(shopping,”, 'ORG')]
I’m not pressured.”
[(pressured.”, 'PERSON')]
The group — 131 that night — sprinted out of the store’s 57th Street entrance, up Fifth Avenue, past the Plaza Hotel and into the southeast entrance to Central Park.
[(Fifth Avenue, 'FAC'), (the Plaza Hotel, 'FAC'), (Central Park, 'LOC')]
Their footwear was varied: some wore New Balance, Saucony, Reebok and Adidas.
[(New Balance, 'ORG'), (Saucony, 'GPE'), (Reebok, 'ORG'), (Adidas, 'PERSON')]
But Nike dominated, and anyone who saw them jogging would surely notice the Nike swoosh on most of their shirts.
[(Nike, 'ORG'), (Nike, 'ORG')]
The group, though sweaty and of varied athletic abilities, flashed by — turning heads of passers-by and other runners.
[]
A human billboard for Nike.
[(Nike, 'ORG')]

[]
2 Americans Among New 23 Cardinals
[(2, 'CARDINAL'), (Americans, 'NORP'), (New 23 Cardinals, 'ORG')]
ROME, Oct. 17 — Pope Benedict XVI named 23 new cardinals on Wednesday, 18 of them under 80 years of age, which qualifies them to take part in an election for a new pope.
[(ROME, 'GPE'), (Oct. 17, 'DATE'), (Benedict XVI, 'PERSON'), (23, 'CARDINAL'), (Wednesday, 'DATE'), (18, 'CARDINAL')]
Of those 18, 10 are from Europe and two from the United States.
[(18, 'CARDINAL'), (10, 'CARDINAL'), (Europe, 'LOC'), (two, 'CARDINAL'), (the United States, 'GPE')]
Daniel N. DiNardo the 58-year old Archbishop of Galveston-Houston, was the more surprising of the American selections.
[(Daniel N. DiNardo, 'PERSON'), (58-year old, 'DATE'), (Galveston-Houston, 'ORG'), (American, 'NORP')]
HE previously worked at the Vatican’s Congregation for Bishops and was named archbishop only last year.
[(the Vatican’s Congregation for Bishops, 'FAC'), (last year, 'DATE')]
His appointment may signal the Pope’s interest in reaching out to the local Latino community.
[(Latino, 'PERSON')]
Archbishop John Patrick Foley was the other of the two Americans selected.
[(John Patrick Foley, 'PERSON'), (two, 'CARDINAL'), (Americans, 'NORP')]
A former journalist and graduate from the Columbia Journalism School, he had been considered a long-time candidate and was active in the communications department under Pope John Paul II.
[(the Columbia Journalism School, 'ORG'), (John Paul II, 'PERSON')]
Archbishop Foley, who is 72, was also recently named grand master of the Equestrian Order of the Holy Sepulcher of Jerusalem, a lay religious community created to protect the rights of the Roman Catholic Church in the Holy Land.
[(Archbishop Foley, 'PERSON'), (72, 'DATE'), (the Equestrian Order of the Holy Sepulcher of Jerusalem, 'ORG'), (the Roman Catholic Church, 'ORG')]
The 23 are to be installed on Nov. 24 at a ceremony known as the consistory, the second such ceremony held under Pope Benedict.
[(23, 'CARDINAL'), (Nov. 24, 'DATE'), (second, 'ORDINAL'), (Benedict, 'PERSON')]
The first was in March last year when he installed 15 new cardinals.
[(first, 'ORDINAL'), (March last year, 'DATE'), (15, 'CARDINAL')]
Ten of the 18 new “cardinal electors” who are under 80 years old are from Europe — four from Italy, two from Spain , and one each from Poland, Germany, France and Ireland.
[(Ten, 'CARDINAL'), (18, 'CARDINAL'), (Europe, 'LOC'), (four, 'CARDINAL'), (Italy, 'GPE'), (two, 'CARDINAL'), (Spain, 'GPE'), (one, 'CARDINAL'), (Poland, 'GPE'), (Germany, 'GPE'), (France, 'GPE'), (Ireland, 'GPE')]
Benedict himself is 80.
[(80, 'DATE')]
Others came from Senegal, India, Argentina, Mexico, Brazil and Kenya.
[(Senegal, 'GPE'), (India, 'GPE'), (Argentina, 'GPE'), (Mexico, 'GPE'), (Brazil, 'GPE'), (Kenya, 'GPE')]
In addition to the 18 electoral cardinals, Benedict named five prelates over the age of 80.
[(18, 'CARDINAL'), (Benedict, 'ORG'), (five, 'CARDINAL'), (the age of 80, 'DATE')]
Included in that list was the Chaldean patriarch of Baghdad, Emmanuel III Delly.
[(Chaldean, 'NORP'), (Baghdad, 'GPE'), (Emmanuel III Delly, 'ORG')]
He has been outspoken about the need to protect minority Christians from persecution and violence in Iraq and his appointment highlights the Pope’s focus on this problem which he has repeatedly referred to in recent months.
[(Christians, 'NORP'), (Iraq, 'GPE'), (recent months, 'DATE')]
Others named were the German Monsignor Joseph Cordes, who heads the Vatican’s charitable works as president of the Pontifical Council "Cor Unum," and the Italian Archbishop Giovanni Lajolo, former Vatican foreign minister and current governor of Vatican City.
[(German, 'NORP'), (Monsignor Joseph Cordes, 'PERSON'), (the Pontifical Council, 'ORG'), (Italian, 'NORP'), (Giovanni Lajolo, 'PERSON'), (Vatican, 'FAC'), (Vatican City, 'GPE')]
Two close aides to Benedicts’ predecessor John Paul II were also chosen: Archbishop Stanislaw Rylko of Poland who is president of the Pontifical Council for Laity and who was present at John Paul’s bedside at his death in 2005 and Archbishop Leonardo Sandri of Argentina, the prefect of the Vatican’s Congregation for Eastern Churches.
[(Two, 'CARDINAL'), (Benedicts’, 'PRODUCT'), (John Paul II, 'PERSON'), (Archbishop Stanislaw Rylko, 'PERSON'), (Poland, 'GPE'), (the Pontifical Council for Laity, 'ORG'), (2005, 'DATE'), (Archbishop Leonardo Sandri, 'PERSON'), (Argentina, 'GPE'), (the Vatican’s Congregation for Eastern Churches, 'ORG')]
He would deliver speeches on behalf of John Paul in the waning days of his pontificate.
[(John Paul, 'PERSON')]
Elector cardinals were named in Paris, Ireland, Rome, Valencia, Barcelona and Genoa.
[(Paris, 'GPE'), (Ireland, 'GPE'), (Rome, 'GPE'), (Valencia, 'GPE'), (Barcelona, 'GPE'), (Genoa, 'GPE')]
They include Archbishop Andre Vingt-Trois of Paris; Sean Baptist Brady, the Archbishop of Armagh and Primate of All Ireland, Angelo Comastri, archpriest of St. Peter’s Basilica, Pope’s vicar-general of the Vatican-City State; Raffaele Farina, archivist of the Holy Roman Church, and Angelo Bagnasco, archbishop of Genoa.
[(Archbishop Andre Vingt-Trois of Paris, 'PERSON'), (Sean Baptist Brady, 'PERSON'), (All Ireland, 'GPE'), (Angelo Comastri, 'PERSON'), (St. Peter’s Basilica, 'ORG'), (Vatican, 'GPE'), (Raffaele Farina, 'PERSON'), (the Holy Roman Church, 'ORG'), (Angelo Bagnasco, 'PERSON'), (Genoa, 'ORG')]
The Spaniards are Agustin Garcia-Gasco Vicente, archbishop of Valencia, Lluis Martinez Sistach, archbishop of Barcelona.
[(Spaniards, 'NORP'), (Agustin Garcia-Gasco Vicente, 'PERSON'), (Valencia, Lluis Martinez Sistach, 'ORG'), (Barcelona, 'GPE')]
The others were Oswald Gracias of Bombay, Francisco Robles Ortega of Monterrey, Mexico, John Njue of Nairobi, Angelo Bagnasco, archbishop of Genoa , Theodore-Adrien Sarr, archbishop of Dakar, Odilio Pedro Scherer, archbishop of Sao Paulo
[(Oswald Gracias, 'PERSON'), (Bombay, 'GPE'), (Robles Ortega, 'PERSON'), (Monterrey, 'GPE'), (Mexico, 'GPE'), (John Njue, 'PERSON'), (Nairobi, 'GPE'), (Angelo Bagnasco, 'PERSON'), (Genoa, 'PERSON'), (Adrien Sarr, 'PERSON'), (Dakar, 'ORG'), (Pedro Scherer, 'PERSON'), (Sao Paulo, 'GPE')]
Cardinals lead dioceses all over the world, are the Pope’s closest aides and are the sole electorate of new pontiffs many of which come from their own ranks.
[]
After the installation of the new appointees, the church will have 202 cardinals, of whom 121 are under 80.
[(202, 'CARDINAL'), (121, 'CARDINAL')]
Normally there are no more than 120 cardinals of voting age.
[]

[]
According to traders, at the close of the New York cash market on Friday, the rate on the outstanding three-month bill was at 3.94 percent, the rate on the six-month issue at 4.04 percent and the rate on the four-week issue was 3.95 percent.
[(New York, 'GPE'), (Friday, 'DATE'), (three-month, 'DATE'), (3.94 percent, 'PERCENT'), (six-month, 'DATE'), (4.04 percent, 'PERCENT'), (four-week, 'DATE'), (3.95 percent, 'PERCENT')]
Spokane, Wash., $58.6 million of general obligation bonds.
[(Spokane, 'GPE'), (Wash., 'GPE'), ($58.6 million, 'MONEY')]
Kentucky State Property and Buildings Commission Project No.
[(Kentucky State Property and Buildings Commission Project No, 'ORG')]
88, $270.7 million of revenue bonds.
[(88, 'CARDINAL'), ($270.7 million, 'MONEY')]
New Orleans, $75 million of general obligation bonds.
[(New Orleans, 'GPE'), ($75 million, 'MONEY')]
Suffolk County, N.Y., $75.7 million of general obligation bonds.
[(Suffolk County, 'GPE'), (N.Y., 'GPE'), ($75.7 million, 'MONEY')]
Tennessee, $150 million of revenue bonds.
[(Tennessee, 'GPE'), ($150 million, 'MONEY')]
Austin Energy, Tex., $50 million of revenue bonds.
[(Austin Energy, 'PERSON'), (Tex., 'GPE'), ($50 million, 'MONEY')]
California Statewide Communities Development Authority, $51 million of refunding revenue bonds for Los Angeles Orthopaedic Hospital Foundation and Orthopaedic Hospital.
[(California Statewide Communities Development Authority, 'ORG'), ($51 million, 'MONEY'), (Los Angeles Orthopaedic Hospital Foundation, 'ORG'), (Orthopaedic Hospital, 'ORG')]
Cass County Hospital, Mo., $50 million of revenue bonds.
[(Cass County Hospital, 'ORG'), (Mo., 'GPE'), ($50 million, 'MONEY')]
Piper Jaffray.
[(Piper Jaffray, 'PERSON')]
City of Phoenix Civic Improvement Corporation, $300 million of junior lien wastewater system revenue bonds.
[(Improvement Corporation, 'ORG'), ($300 million, 'MONEY')]
Hillsborough County, Fla., Industrial Development Authority, $119.1 million of hospital revenue refunding bonds for H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center.
[(Hillsborough County, 'GPE'), (Fla., 'GPE'), (Industrial Development Authority, 'ORG'), ($119.1 million, 'MONEY'), (H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center, 'PERSON')]
Louisiana Local Government Environmental Facilities and Community Development Authority, City of Bossier, City Public Improvements Projects, $100 million of revenue bonds.
[(Louisiana Local Government Environmental Facilities, 'ORG'), (Community Development Authority, 'ORG'), ($100 million, 'MONEY')]
Louisiana Public Facilities Authority, $300 million of debt securities for Hurricane Recovery Program.
[(Louisiana Public Facilities Authority, 'ORG'), ($300 million, 'MONEY'), (Hurricane Recovery Program, 'ORG')]
Morgan Keegan.
[(Morgan Keegan, 'ORG')]
Massachusetts Housing Finance Agency, $107 million of debt securities.
[(Massachusetts Housing Finance Agency, 'ORG'), ($107 million, 'MONEY')]
Missouri Environmental Improvement and Energy Resources Authority, $56.7 million of debt securities.
[(Missouri Environmental Improvement and Energy Resources Authority, 'ORG'), ($56.7 million, 'MONEY')]
North Carolina Medical Care Commission Retirement Facilities, $62.6 million of first mortgage revenue bonds.
[(North Carolina Medical Care Commission Retirement Facilities, 'ORG'), ($62.6 million, 'MONEY'), (first, 'ORDINAL')]
Ziegler Capital Markets.
[(Ziegler Capital Markets, 'ORG')]
Overland Park Development Corporation, $109 million of debt securities for Sheraton Overland Park.
[(Overland Park Development Corporation, 'ORG'), ($109 million, 'MONEY'), (Sheraton Overland Park, 'FAC')]
